[NOISE] Okay everyone, let's get started for today.
[NOISE]大家好，让我们今天开始吧。
Okay. So, we're into week five of CS224n.
好的。所以，我们进入了CS224n的第五周。
And so, this is the plan for today.
所以，这是今天的计划。
Um, in some sense a lot of this class is gonna be
嗯，从某种意义上说，这个课程很多都会
an easy class because I'm gonna talk about things like,
一个简单的课程，因为我会谈论像，
um, final projects and tips for what you're meant to do,
嗯，关于你打算做什么的最终项目和提示，
and finding a topic,
并找到一个主题，
and writing up your work,
并写下你的工作，
and things like that.
和那样的事情。
Um, so for, um, so,
嗯，所以，嗯，所以，
two-thirds of the class there isn't a lot of,
三分之二的班级没有很多，
um, deep technical content.
嗯，技术含量很高。
But I hope they're actually
但我希望他们真的
just some useful stuff and stuff that would be good to know about.
只是一些有用的东西和东西，这将是很好的了解。
One way you can think about this is until,
你能想到的一种方法是，直到，
until this year we had a midterm in this class.
直到今年我们在这个班级中期。
So, you know, if we weren't doing this class should instead be doing the
所以，你知道，如果我们不做这个课，应该做的
the mid-term based on all the material that we've covered, um, so far.
到目前为止，中期基于我们所涵盖的所有材料。
So, this should be really pleasant by comparison.
所以，相比之下，这应该是非常愉快的。
Um, but that isn't gonna be quite the entire class.
嗯，但这不会是整个班级。
So, for this piece here in the middle I'm gonna
所以，对于这件作品，我会在中间
spend a while back on some of the topics of last week.
花一点时间回顾上周的一些主题。
So, I wanted to have one more look at some of these gated recurrent models,
所以，我想再看一些这些门控循环模型，
um, that Abby introduced last week.
嗯，Abby上周介绍过。
And I guess my hope is that now that you've
我想我的希望就是现在你已经
had a bit more time to look and read about things,
有更多的时间来查看和阅读事物，
and hopefully even have started working on homework for that.
并希望甚至已经开始为此做功课。
Maybe it starts to make a bit more sense or else even if it's more confusing then before,
也许它开始变得更有意义，否则即使它之前更加混乱，
you've got some idea of what your confusions are and questions.
你已经了解了你的困惑和问题。
And so, hopefully it's, um,
所以，希望是的，嗯，
good to think about those one more time because I think they are quite a complex notion,
好好再考虑那些，因为我认为它们是一个相当复杂的概念，
and it's not so obvious what they're doing and why they're doing anything useful,
他们正在做什么以及为什么他们做任何有用的事情都不是那么明显，
or whether they're just this big complex blob of mystery.
或者他们是否只是这个复杂的大谜团。
And then also to touch on a couple of machine translation topics that have um, come up
然后还要谈谈有几个机器翻译主题的问题
in the final project that we didn't really get m- time to say much about last week.
在最后一个项目中，我们并没有真正得到上周的时间。
[NOISE] Okay.
[NOISE]好的。
So, let's get started.
那么，让我们开始吧。
Um, so, this is our coursework in grading that we showed at the beginning.
嗯，这是我们在开始时展示的评分课程。
And so, the main thing I wanna do today is talk about this final project.
所以，我今天要做的主要事情是谈论这个最终项目。
Um, but before tha- I do that,
嗯，但在此之前 - 我这样做，
let's just save one minute on participation.
让我们节省一分钟参与。
Um, so, I guess we started into one aspect of the participation policy, um,
嗯，所以，我想我们开始参与政策的一个方面，嗯，
last Thursday when we took attendance,
上周四我们参加时，
and that makes it sound draconian,
这让它听起来很苛刻，
but I wanted to say, um,
但我想说，嗯，
the positive viewpoint of,
积极的观点，
um, the participation points.
嗯，参与点。
I mean, obviously this is a big class.
我的意思是，显然这是一个很大的课程。
There are lots of people.
有很多人。
Um, our hope is just that people will variously,
嗯，我们的希望只是人们会各种各样，
they're sort of engaged and involved in the class,
他们有点参与和参与课程，
and the participation points,
和参与点，
ah, are our way of doing that.
啊，是我们这样做的方式。
I mean, basically the way this is set up.
我的意思是，基本上这是建立的方式。
I mean, if you do much of anything
我的意思是，如果你做了很多事情
you should just get three percent for the participation points.
你应该只获得3％的参与积分。
It shouldn't be hard.
这应该不难。
I mean, I will bet you that there will be some people who at the end,
我的意思是，我敢打赌你会有一些人到最后，
will have gotten seven points in the participation category.
将在参与类别中获得7分。
And unfortunately we cap you, we'll only give you
不幸的是，我们限制你，我们只会给你
three percent for the participation category, but you know,
参与类别的百分之三，但是你知道，
providing you usually come to class,
通常你来上课，
or usually write the,
或者通常写，
um, what we've got to [NOISE] the invited speakers
嗯，我们得到了[NOISE]邀请的演讲者
the reaction paragraphs if you are an SCPD student.
如果您是SCPD学生，请参阅反应段落。
Sometimes, um, write a helpful answer on Piazza, right.
有时，嗯，在Piazza上写一个有用的答案吧。
You're already gonna be there on three percent.
你已经有百分之三的存在了。
Um, yeah.
嗯，是的
And so, one, but one other thing, um,
所以，一个，但另一个，嗯，
that's a way to get some parti- participation points that's out today.
这是一种获得今天的参与点的方法。
So, um, today we're putting up our Mid-quarter feedback survey.
所以，嗯，今天我们正在进行我们的中期季度反馈调查。
And we'd love to have you fill that in.
我们很乐意让你填补它。
I mean, we'd like to get your thoughts on the course so far.
我的意思是，我们希望到目前为止对你的课程有所了解。
And, you know, for you guys,
而且，你知道，对你们这些人来说，
there are two ways that you can win.
你可以通过两种方式获胜。
First if you give us some feedback that can help the rest of your quarter be better,
首先，如果你给我们一些反馈，可以帮助你的季度的其余部分更好，
but we've also got a simple bribe built into this, um,
但我们也有一个简单的贿赂，嗯，
which is you get half a participation point simply for filling in,
你只需填写一半的参与点，
um, the, um, Mid-quarter survey,
嗯，嗯，中季度调查，
but it'd be really good to get your feedback on that.
但收到你的反馈真的很好。
Okay. So, then the main thing I want to get to
好的。那么，那就是我想要达到的主要内容
today is to talk about [NOISE] the final project.
今天是谈谈[NOISE]最后的项目。
Okay. And so, I'll jump right ahead, um, into that.
好的。所以，我会直接向前跳，嗯，进入那个。
So, for the final project there are two choices.
因此，对于最终项目，有两种选择。
Um, you, you can either do our default final project,
嗯，你，你可以做我们默认的最终项目，
which I'll say a little bit about, it's doing SQuAD question answering,
我会说一点点，它正在做SQUAD问题回答，
or you can propose a final,
或者你可以提出决赛，
a custom final project,
自定义最终项目，
which we then have to approve.
然后我们必须批准。
And in the course of that,
在此过程中，
um, if you have some outside mentor, um,
嗯，如果你有一些外面的导师，嗯，
you can say who they are and your project proposal,
你可以说出他们是谁和你的项目提案，
but otherwise, um, we'll attempt to assign you a mentor somewhere out of the course staff.
但除此之外，嗯，我们会尝试在课程工作人员的某个地方为您指派一名导师。
Um, so, for all the assignments,
嗯，对于所有作业，
through assignments one through five,
通过作业一至五，
you have to do them by yourself.
你必须自己做。
Um, for the final project in either form of that,
嗯，对于任何一种形式的最终项目，
you can do it as a team.
你可以团队合作。
So, you can do it as one,
所以，你可以做到一个，
two, or three people.
两个或三个人。
And how does that work?
这是如何工作的？
Um, well, it works like this, um,
嗯，它的工作方式是这样的，嗯，
if you're a bigger team,
如果你是一个更大的团队，
we do expect you to do more,
我们希望你做更多，
and there are actually two ways you can be a bigger team that I'll point out.
我会指出，实际上有两种方法可以成为一个更大的团队。
One way is having more people being two or three people.
一种方法是让更多的人成为两三个人。
And the other thing that comes up is, um,
而另一件事是，嗯，
sometimes people wanna do a final project for more than one class at the same time.
有时人们想要同时为多个班级做最后的项目。
In particular for this quarter I know there are
特别是本季度我知道有
at least a couple of people who are hoping to do,
至少有几个人希望这样做，
um, a joint project with Emma's reinforcement learning class.
嗯，与艾玛的强化学习课程的联合项目。
And we allow that as well.
我们也允许这样做。
But we sort of do multiplication because if you're two people using it for two classes,
但是我们会做乘法，因为如果你有两个人用它来做两个班，
that means it should be four times as great as
这意味着它应该是它的四倍
what one person is doing for one class, right?
一个人为一个班级做了什么，对吧？
So, how, how it works with larger teams, you know,
那么，如何，如何与大型团队合作，你知道，
in all honesty it's a little bit subtle because, you know,
老实说它有点微妙，因为，你知道，
the truth is if something is just bad, um,
事实是，如果事情是坏的，嗯，
your model was broken, um,
你的模型坏了，嗯，
or you, your experiment failed,
或者你，你的实验失败了，
um, and you don't know why.
嗯，你不知道为什么。
Um, you know. If, if there's just obvious ways in what you've done as bad as it's sort of,
嗯，你知道。如果，如果你所做的事情只有明显的方式那么糟糕，
it's sort of bad whether you're one person or four person.
无论你是一个人还是四个人，这都很糟糕。
Um, and if you've written it up beautifully,
嗯，如果你把它写得很漂亮，
you've written up beautifully regardless of whether
无论是否，你都写得很漂亮
you're one person or four per- people,
你是一个人或四个人，
that you know nevertheless the expectation is that if you're one person will be pleased,
但你知道的是，如果你是一个人会很高兴，
that if you put together one model and gotten it to work well, um,
如果你把一个模型放在一起并让它运作良好，嗯，
but if you're three people will say, "Well,
但如果你有三个人会说，“嗯，
that wasn't such a big effort, um,
那不是那么大的努力，嗯，
running this one model against this task."
针对这个任务运行这个模型。“
Surely if there are three people,
当然如果有三个人，
they could have investigated
他们本可以调查一下
some other model classes and seeing whether they perform better or worse on this task.
一些其他模型类，看看它们在这项任务上的表现是好还是坏。
And we'll feel a sense of lightweight.
我们会感受到轻盈感。
So, we are expecting that sort of both more ambitious projects,
所以，我们期待这两个更雄心勃勃的项目，
and more thorough exploration of them if you're
如果你有更深入的探索它们
being a bigger team or you're using it for multiple classes.
成为一个更大的团队，或者你正在将它用于多个班级。
Um, for the final project,
嗯，对于最后的项目，
you are allowed to use any language or deep learning,
你被允许使用任何语言或深度学习，
um, framework that you choose to.
嗯，你选择的框架。
We don't insist on what you use,
我们不坚持你使用的东西，
though in practice in past years.
虽然在过去几年的实践中。
Basically everyone keeps on using what they've learned,
基本上每个人都在继续使用他们所学到的东西，
um, in the assignments.
嗯，在作业中。
I expect that will be true, um,
我希望那是真的，嗯，
this time as well. [NOISE]
这次也是。 [噪声]
Okay. So, um, let me just mention quickly the default final project,
好的。那么，嗯，让我快速提一下默认的最终项目，
so that you've got, um,
所以，你有，嗯，
some sense of context.
一些背景感。
So, the materials of that will be released this Thursday.
因此，该材料将于本周四发布。
And so, for the tasks for it is,
因此，对于它的任务是，
a textural question-answering task which is done over the,
一个质地问答工作，完成了，
the Stanford Question Answering Dataset, SQuAD,
斯坦福问题答疑数据集，SQuAD，
which was a dataset put together, um,
这是一个放在一起的数据集，嗯，
by Percy Liang and the department and the student .
Percy Liang和部门和学生。
Um, so, we've used this as a default final project,
嗯，所以，我们已经将它用作默认的最终项目，
um, before but we're mixing up a couple of things this year.
嗯，之前我们今年混淆了几件事。
I mean, firstly, the starter code we're providing this year is in pytorch,
我的意思是，首先，我们今年提供的入门代码是pytorch，
to fit in with what we've done to the rest of the class.
以适应我们对班上其他人所做的事情。
But secondly, the SQuAD team,
但其次，SQuAD团队，
released a new version of SQuAD,
发布了新版SQuAD，
SQuAD 2,0 and we're going to use that for the class this year.
SQuAD 2,0，今年我们将在课堂上使用它。
And the essential difference in SQuAD 2,0,
和SQuAD 2,0的本质区别，
is in SQuAD 1,1 or 1,0,
在SQuAD 1,1或1,0中，
every question had an answer in the passage of text whereas in SQuAD 2,0,
每个问题在文本的通过中都有答案，而在SQUAD 2,0中，
a lot of questions don't have answers.
很多问题都没有答案。
So, there's this extra significant thing that you need to do which is working out,
所以，你需要做的就是这个非常重要的事情，
um, whether a question has an answer.
嗯，问题是否有答案。
So, th- this is just one example,
所以，这只是一个例子，
um, which just gives you a sense of the SQuAD,  what SQuAD is like.
嗯，这只是让你感觉SQuAD，SQUAD是什么样的。
So, there's a paragraph of text.
所以，有一段文字。
I've just put a subset of it here, um, Bill Aken,
我刚才把它的一部分放在这里，呃，比尔阿肯，
adopted by Mexican movie actress, Lupe Mayorga, um,
被墨西哥电影女演员Lupe Mayorga收养，嗯，
grew up in the neighborhood town, neighboring, sorry,
在附近的小镇长大，邻居，抱歉，
neighboring town of Madeira and his song chronicled
邻近的马德拉镇和他的歌曲记录
the hardships faced by the migrant farm workers he saw as a child.
他小时候看到的农民工所面临的艰辛。
Right, there's then a question, um,
对，那就是一个问题，嗯，
in what town did Bill,
比尔在哪个城镇，
right, actually I misspelled that sorry,
对，实际上我拼错了那个抱歉，
it should have been Aken without an I. I got confused with our former department chair,
应该是没有我的阿肯。我和我们以前的部门主席混淆了
Alex Aiken, I guess when I was typing.
Alex Aiken，我猜我在打字的时候。
Um, Bill Aken grow up?
嗯，比尔阿肯长大了？
And the answer you are meant to give is Madeira.
而你要给出的答案是马德拉。
Um, so, just incidentally,
嗯，顺便说一下，
it's a random fact.
这是随机的事实。
Um, so, quite a few of you know about something that was
嗯，所以，你们中的很多人都知道这件事
recently in the kind of tech news, tech
最近在科技新闻，科技
news and we're going to talk about later in the class.
新闻，我们将在课堂上讨论。
Um, that people, um,
嗯，那个人，嗯，
from Google produced this very strong New Natural Language
来自谷歌的这种非常强大的新自然语言
Understanding representation model called BERT.
理解称为BERT的表示模型。
And which is one of several kind of models that are in a class of,
这是一类中的几种模型之一，
models that contextually model words that have come into prominence in 2017 and 18.
模型在上下文中模拟了在2017年和18年突出的词汇。
And in general, BERT has sort of produced very good performance for very many tasks.
总的来说，BERT对很多任务都有很好的表现。
Indeed, if you look at the SQuAD 2,0 leader board online, um,
的确，如果你在网上看看SQuAD 2,0排行榜，嗯，
at this URL, what you'll find is that
在这个URL，你会发现是什么
all of the leading systems use BERT in some way or another, these days.
如今，所有领先的系统都以某种方式使用BERT。
Um, but nevertheless, this was actually a question that BERT got wrong.
嗯，但是，这实际上是BERT出错的问题。
Um, that BERT said,
嗯，BERT说，
"No answer to this question,
“这个问题没有答案，
" rather than getting the correct answer.
“而不是得到正确的答案。
Even though it looks kind of straightforward reading it as a human being.
即使它看起来像人类一样直截了当。
It doesn't really look a human tricky reading comprehension question.
它实际上并不是一个人类棘手的阅读理解问题。
Um, so, that's the default final project.
嗯，这是默认的最终项目。
So, on Thursday, I'm going to talk more about the default final project.
因此，在周四，我将更多地讨论默认的最终项目。
I'm going to talk about how people build textual question answering systems.
我将谈谈人们如何构建文本问答系统。
And the details on the default final project should all be posted by then,
那时默认的最终项目的详细信息都应该发布，
but that's just to give you a bit of context of what the other choice is.
但这只是为了给你一些关于另一种选择的背景。
And today, I'm sort of more going to be aiming at people,
而今天，我更倾向于瞄准人，
um, doing the custom final project.
嗯，做自定义最终项目。
But let me just sort of say a bit first about the choice between the two of them.
但是，让我先谈谈他们两人之间的选择。
So, um, why might you want to choose the default final project?
那么，嗯，为什么你想选择默认的最终项目？
So, if you have limited experience with research,
所以，如果你的研究经验有限，
you don't have any clear idea of a research project you want to do this quarter,
你对本季你想做的研究项目没有任何明确的想法，
you're just really busy with other classes that, uh,
你真的很忙于其他课程，呃，
you're enrolled in CS140 and you're just really loade- loaded
你已经注册了CS140并且你真的很厌烦
[LAUGHTER] now with other classes you're doing this quarter.
[笑声]现在和你本季度正在做的其他课程一样。
Um, you'd be happy to have just a clear goal towards, to work towards.
嗯，你很乐意有一个明确的目标，努力工作。
A leaderboard of your fellow students that you can compete against.
你可以与之竞争的同学的排行榜。
Um, do the default final project.
嗯，做默认的最终项目。
Um, I think for many people it's actually the good right choice.
嗯，我认为对很多人来说，这实际上是一个很好的选择。
And I mean, for what it's worth, I mean,
我的意思是，对于它的价值，我的意思是，
typically, slightly over half of people have done the default final project.
通常，略超过一半的人完成了默认的最终项目。
It's normally that, so 55 percent have done
通常情况下，55％的人已经这样做了
the default final project and the rest the custom final project.
默认的最终项目，其余的是自定义的最终项目。
So, if you do the default final project,
所以，如果你做默认的最终项目，
you'll get lots of guidance.
你会得到很多指导。
You get lots of scaffolding.
你有很多脚手架。
There are clear things to aim at in what you do.
你所做的事情有明确的目标。
Um, the course staff are in general most prepared and most able to help you.
嗯，课程的工作人员一般都准备最充分，最能帮到你。
Um, and in particular,
嗯，特别是，
I mean, the, for the bottom bullet here.
我的意思是，这里的底部子弹。
I mean, you know, something to think about in making
我的意思是，你知道，在制作时要考虑一些事情
the choices that some of it comes down to how committed,
其中一些选择归结为如何承诺，
organized, and keen are you to be wanting to do your own custom final project.
有条不紊，你想要做自己的自定义最终项目。
If you've got a, something you really want to do for a custom final project, great.
如果你有一个，你真的想要为自定义的最终项目做些什么，那很好。
We love to see interesting custom final projects.
我们喜欢看有趣的自定义最终项目。
But, you know, if you're going to end up doing something that just looks
但是，你知道，如果你最终会做一些看起来很像的东西
worse like [LAUGHTER] not done as well [LAUGHTER] as you would've done a, done a project.
更糟糕的是[笑声]没有完成[笑声]，就像你做的那样，做了一个项目。
If you'd just done the fin-, default final project,
如果你刚刚完成了fin-，默认的最终项目，
then you should probably choose the default final project [LAUGHTER].
那你应该选择默认的最终项目[笑声]。
Um, okay.
嗯，好的。
But even if you are doing,
但即使你这样做，
think you'll do the default final project.
认为你会做默认的最终项目。
I hope that some of this lecture will still, um, be useful.
我希望这个讲座中的某些内容仍然有用。
While the part in the middle, when I talk back about
当我在谈论时，中间的部分
MT and Gater or current networks are definitely useful.
MT和Gater或当前网络绝对有用。
But, you know, beyond that, um,
但是，你知道，除此之外，嗯，
some of the tips on doing research and discussions of,
关于做研究和讨论的一些技巧，
sort of looking at how to make neural networks work and error analysis, paper writing.
有点看着如何使神经网络工作和错误分析，论文写作。
These are all good topics that apply to the default final project as well.
这些都是适用于默认最终项目的好主题。
So, in the other direction, um,
那么，在另一个方向，嗯，
if you have some research project that you're excited about.
如果你有一些你很兴奋的研究项目。
Possibly, it's one you are already working on or possibly,
可能，这是你已经或正在工作的那个，
that you've just always wished to do.
你一直都希望这样做。
Something exciting with neural networks and rap music.
令人兴奋的神经网络和说唱音乐。
Um, well, you know, that custom final project is an opportunity to do that.
嗯，嗯，你知道，那个定制的最终项目是一个做到这一点的机会。
Um, so, it's a chance for you to do something on your own.
嗯，这是你自己做点什么的机会。
Um, it, you know, obviously,
嗯，你知道，显然，
if you're not interested in textural question-answering
如果你对纹理问答不感兴趣
but do you think you might like machine translation.
但你认为你可能喜欢机器翻译吗？
Well, it's an opportunity, um,
嗯，这是一个机会，嗯，
to choose any topic of your own.
选择你自己的任何话题。
It's also a way to sort of experience much more of the research pro- process because,
这也是一种经验更多的研究过程，因为，
you know, for the default final project, it's a bigger,
你知道，对于默认的最终项目，它是一个更大的，
more open-ended thing than any of our assignments.
比我们任何任务更开放的东西。
But, you know, nevertheless,
但是，你知道，
the default final project is still
默认的最终项目仍然是
sort of a pre-setup thing that you don't have to find your own problem,
一种预设的东西，你不必找到自己的问题，
find your own data,
找到你自己的数据，
work out a good approach to it.
找出一个很好的方法。
A lot of that's sort of been done for you.
很多都是为你做的。
So, that, for a custom final project it's much more
所以，对于自定义的最终项目来说，它更多
your own job to sort of define and execute a mini research project.
你自己的工作，以定义和执行一个迷你研究项目。
And so, if all of that stuff seems appealing or some of it seems appealing,
所以，如果所有这些东西看起来很吸引人或者其中一些似乎很吸引人，
um, then aim at the custom final project.
嗯，然后瞄准定制的最终项目。
Um, doing this just reminded me about a fact about assignments one to five.
嗯，这样做只是让我想起了关于一到五个作业的事实。
You know, for assignments one to five,
你知道，对于一到五个作业，
we are hoping that they can be a set of stepping
我们希望他们可以成为一套踩踏
stones for learning how to build deep learning systems.
学习如何建立深度学习系统的石头。
But, you know, one of our goals in that is to give you less hand holds as time goes by.
但是，你知道，我们的目标之一就是随着时间的推移减少手数。
So, you know, assignment one was really easy and assignment three,
所以，你知道，任务一个非常简单，任务三，
we tried to make it really handholdy,
我们试图让它真的很自负，
so people could start to learn PyTorch.
所以人们可以开始学习PyTorch。
But, you know, we're actually hoping for assignments
但是，你知道，我们实际上是希望分配
four and five that they're actually harder,
四，五，他们实际上更难，
so that you're getting more experience of working
这样你就可以获得更多的工作经验
out how to build and do things by yourself
如何自己建造和做事
because if the only thing you ever see is completely scaffolded assignments.
因为如果你看到的唯一的东西是完全脚手架的任务。
It's sort of like when you do CS106A that you have to do a great job on
这有点像你做CS106A时你必须做得很好
the CS106A assignments but you don't really know how to write a program by yourselves.
CS106A的任务，但你真的不知道如何自己编写程序。
And that's sort of what we want to, um,
这就是我们想要的，嗯，
sort of get you beyond,
有点让你超越，
um, in the latter two assignments.
嗯，在后两个任务中。
So, I hope you have started on assignment four.
所以，我希望你已经完成了第四项任务。
If not, you really should start and get underway soon as Abby was emphasizing.
如果没有，你真的应该开始并在Abby强调的时候开始。
Okay. So, this year for the,
好的。那么，今年为了，
um, final project, whichever one you're doing.
嗯，最后的项目，无论你在做什么。
Um, we're actually putting more structure in than we have
嗯，我们实际上比我们拥有更多的结构
in previous years to encourage people to get going.
在往年鼓励人们开始。
And so, in particular,
特别是，
there are early on components which are worth points in the grading.
早期的组件在评分中是值得的。
So, the first part of that is a project proposal,
所以，第一部分是项目提案，
um, which is, um,
嗯，嗯，
we want from each team.
我们希望每个团队。
So, one per team, um,
那么，每个团队一个，嗯，
you can just do a joint one,
你可以做一个联合的，
um, which is worth five percent.
嗯，这个价值百分之五。
Um, so, it's, we're releasing the details on Thursday which is when
嗯，所以，我们将在星期四发布详细信息
assignment four is due and it'll be due the following Thursday.
作业四是到期，它将在下周四到期。
So, we're actually having an interruption in the sequence of current assignments, right.
所以，我们实际上正在分配当前分配的顺序，对吧。
So, for the next week, um,
那么，下周，嗯，
what the thing to do is project proposal.
要做的是项目提案。
And then the week after that, um,
然后一周之后，嗯，
we're back to assignment five and then we go full time into final project.
我们回到第五项任务，然后我们全职进入最终项目。
So, what we're wanting for
那么，我们想要的是什么
the project proposal is we're actually wanting you to do a little bit
项目建议是我们真的希望你做一点点
of starting off research and the fine ter- terms of reading some paper.
开始研究和阅读一些论文的细微术语。
So, find some paper that's, um,
所以，找一些纸，嗯，
relevant to your research,
与您的研究相关，
um, that you are going to do.
嗯，你要去做。
Um, read it, write a summary of what it does.
嗯，阅读它，写下它的作用摘要。
Um, write down some thoughts on how you could adapt or extend ideas in it,
嗯，写下一些关于如何适应或扩展其中的想法的想法，
in your own final project.
在你自己的最终项目中。
Um, and then say something about what your plan is for
嗯，然后说一下你的计划是什么
what you're goi- hoping to do for your final project.
您希望为最终项目做些什么。
And especially, if you're doing a custom final project
特别是，如果你正在做一个自定义的最终项目
there's more to write there because we'll want to make
还有更多要写在那里因为我们想做
sure that you have some idea as to
确定你有一些想法
what data you can use and how are you going to evaluate it.
您可以使用哪些数据以及如何评估它。
Whereas a couple of those things are actually sort of
而实际上有几件事实际上是那样的
determined for you if you're doing the default final project.
如果您正在进行默认的最终项目，请确定。
Um, and so then after that we're going to have a project milestone, um,
嗯，那之后我们将有一个项目里程碑，嗯，
which is the progress report where we're hoping that you can
这是进度报告，我们希望你可以
report that you're well along in your final project.
报告说你在最后的项目中表现良好。
That you've run at least some experiment and have
你已经至少进行了一些实验并且已经完成了
some results on some data that you can talk about.
您可以谈论的一些数据的一些结果。
So the default- the project milestone is due on,
所以默认 - 项目里程碑到期，
um, Thursday, March seven.
嗯，星期四，3月7日。
So it's actually more than halfway through
所以它实际上超过了一半
the period that's sort of dedicated to the final project.
那个专门用于最终项目的时期。
So, if you are not- we sort of put it past
所以，如果你不是 - 我们有点过去了
halfway because the fact of the matter is it always takes people time to get going,
中途因为事情的事实总是需要时间才能开始，
um, but nevertheless, you know,
嗯，但是，你知道，
what you should have in your head is unless you're halfway
除非你是中途，否则你应该拥有的是什么
through by the time you're handing in your,
当你递交你的时候，
um, project milestone, then you're definitely behind.
嗯，项目里程碑，然后你肯定落后了。
And you'll be doing that typical Stanford thing of having a lot of late nights
而且你会做那种典型的斯坦福大学有很多深夜的事情
and lack of sleep in the last week [LAUGHTER] of class trying to catch up for that.
上周[笑声]班级试图赶上那个并且睡眠不足。
Um, okay. So, um,
嗯，好的。那么，嗯，
so now I've sort of, um,
所以现在我有点，嗯，
want to sort of just start saying a bit of- for
想要开始说一点点
custom final projects of some of the sort of
一些自定义的最终项目
thinking and types of things that you could do about that.
思考和你可以做的事情类型。
Um, so you have to determine some project,
嗯，所以你必须确定一些项目，
um, for- if you're doing a custom final project.
嗯，因为你正在做一个自定义的最终项目。
So, in philosophy of science, you know,
所以，在科学哲学中，你知道，
there are basically two ways for any field you can have a project.
对于任何可以拥有项目的字段，基本上有两种方法。
You either start with some domain problem of interest.
您要么从一些感兴趣的域问题开始。
You're [NOISE] just got something you're interested in or say,
你[NOISE]只是得到你感兴趣或说的东西，
"Gee, I'd like to do better machine translation."
“哎呀，我想做更好的机器翻译。”
And then you work out some ways to address it with technology,
然后你找到了一些用技术来解决它的方法，
or you start with some, um,
或者你从一些人开始，嗯，
technical approach of interest.
技术方法。
And you say, "Oh well,
你说，“哦，好吧，
those LSTMs seemed kind of neat,
那些LSTM看起来很整洁，
but I didn't understand why there's
但我不明白为什么会这样
that extra 10H and I think it'd be better if it changed in this other way.
额外的10H，我认为如果以其他方式改变它会更好。
And you start exploring from a technical direction to try and come up with a better idea.
你开始从技术方向探索，尝试提出一个更好的主意。
And then you're wanting to prove that it works.
然后你想要证明它有效。
So in kinds of the projects that people do for this class,
所以在人们为这个班级做的各种项目中，
this isn't quite an exhaustive list,
这不是一个详尽的清单，
but this is sort of in general what people do.
但这通常是人们的行为。
So, the first category and really I think this
所以，第一类，我真的认为这一点
is the bulk of projects over half is people find
是人们发现的大部分项目超过一半
some task replication of interest and they build
一些任务复制的兴趣和他们建立
some neural network models to try and do it as effectively as possible.
一些神经网络模型尽可能有效地尝试。
Um, there's a second category where people sort of concentrate on implementing,
嗯，还有第二类人们专注于实施，
so re-implementing some complex neural architecture and getting it to work on some data.
所以重新实现一些复杂的神经体系结构并使其能够处理一些数据。
And so let me just say a couple of sentences on this.
所以，我只想对此说几句话。
Um, so, it's certainly okay for you to,
嗯，这对你来说当然没问题，
um, start by re-implementing some existing model.
嗯，首先重新实现一些现有的模型。
Um, and some people that's as far as they get.
嗯，有些人就是他们得到的。
And then the question is, um, is that okay?
然后问题是，嗯，好吗？
And the answer to whether that's okay sort
以及这是否合适的答案
of largely depends on how complex your neural model is.
很大程度上取决于你的神经模型是多么复杂。
Um, so if what you think is okay I'm going to, um,
嗯，如果你认为我没事，我会，
re-implement something like we've seen already,
重新实现我们已经看过的东西，
like a window-based classification model and you
像基于窗口的分类模型和你
just re-implement that and run it on some data and get some results and stop.
只需重新实现它并在某些数据上运行它并获得一些结果并停止。
That's definitely a bad project.
这绝对是一个糟糕的项目。
Um, but there are lots of very complicated and sophisticated neural,
嗯，但是有很多非常复杂和复杂的神经，
um, architectures out there.
嗯，那里的建筑。
And if you're trying to do something complicated well then that can be a fine project.
如果你想做一些复杂的事情那么这可能是一个很好的项目。
Um, so, I actually sort of stuck in a few examples of projects.
嗯，所以，我实际上有点困在几个项目的例子中。
So, I mean, here's one that was actually from a couple of years ago.
所以，我的意思是，这是几年前的实际情况。
Um, so this was in the 2017 class.
嗯，所以这是2017年的课程。
And so, shortly before the 2017 class,
所以，在2017年的课程前不久，
"Deep Mind" who's one of the um, organizations producing
“深刻的心灵”谁是组织生产的组织之一
the most complicated neural models had just released
最复杂的神经模型刚刚发布
a paper about the differentiable neural computer model,
关于可微分神经计算机模型的论文，
which was a model of how to have something like
这是一个如何拥有类似东西的模型
a differentiate- differentiable Turing machine-like
差异化的图灵机
architecture inside a neural network, um,
神经网络内部的架构，嗯，
and  thought, um,
并且想，嗯，
this would be a great challenge to try and, um,
尝试这是一个很大的挑战，嗯，
re-implement the differentiable neural computer which Deep Mind hadn't released
重新实现Deep Mind尚未发布的可微分神经计算机
any source code for because they're not the kind of
任何源代码因为它们不是那种
place that generally releases their source code.
通常发布源代码的地方。
Um, and, you know, this was actually an extremely ambitious project because it
嗯，而且，你知道，这实际上是一个非常雄心勃勃的项目，因为它
was, it's a very complex architecture which is hard to get to train.
是的，这是一个非常复杂的建筑，很难训练。
And so, you know, at the end,
所以，你知道，最后，
at the end she hadn't been able to sort of train as
最后，她没能像火车一样
big a model or get as good results as they report in the paper that,
大模型或获得与他们在论文中报告的结果一样好的结果，
you know, frankly we thought it was pretty
你知道，坦率地说，我们认为这很漂亮
miraculous that she managed to get it working at all.
神奇的是，她设法让它工作。
In the period of time we had in the class and she did successfully do an open-source
在我们上课的那段时间里，她成功地做了一个开源
re-implementation of this model which basically worked the same as in their paper.
重新实施这个模型，基本上和他们的论文一样。
Though not quite as well.
虽然不太好。
So, you know, that seemed a huge achievement.
所以，你知道，这似乎是一项巨大的成就。
So, you certainly can do something of that sort.
所以，你当然可以做那种事情。
Right. So, um, so you- you can sort of from
对。所以，嗯，所以你 - 你可以从中分类
a technical direction have some ideas for variant model and explore,
技术方向对变体模型有一些想法和探索，
um, how to make a different kind of model class and then look
嗯，如何制作一个不同类型的模型然后看
at how it works on some problem that works well.
如何解决一些运作良好的问题。
Another kind of project you can do is an analysis project,
您可以做的另一种项目是分析项目，
so that you might be interested in something in
这样你就可能对某些东西感兴趣了
natural language or something on the behavior of neural networks,
自然语言或神经网络行为的东西，
and just think that you want to analyze them more closely.
并且只是认为你想更仔细地分析它们。
So, you might think, "Oh,
所以，你可能会想，“哦，
maybe these neural machine translation systems work great
也许这些神经机器翻译系统运行良好
providing the word order is the same in the source and target language,
提供单词顺序在源语言和目标语言中是相同的，
but can they really do a good job of reordering phrases for different language types?
但他们真的可以很好地重新排序不同语言类型的短语吗？
How much does their performance vary based on
他们的表现有多大差异
the amount of reordering between the source and target language?"
源语言和目标语言之间的重新排序量？“
And you could do some experiments to try and
你可以尝试做一些实验
investigate that as an analysis problem that looks at a model,
调查作为一个分析问题，看一个模型，
and we sometimes get projects like that.
我们有时会得到这样的项目。
Down at the bottom is the rarest kind of project,
在底部是最稀有的项目，
which is when some people try to do something
这是有些人试图做某事的时候
theoretical which is to prove some properties of a system.
理论是证明一个系统的某些属性。
So if- this is easiest to do in simple systems for something like word vectors,
所以，如果 - 这对于像单词向量这样的简单系统来说最容易做到，
that if you might want to prove something about
如果你想证明一些事情
the kind of spaces that are induced by word vectors,
由词向量引起的那种空间，
and what properties you need to have in
以及你需要拥有什么属性
models for word analogies to work or something like that.
单词类比工作的模型或类似的东西。
Um here are just another couple of examples that so- shows some of the other classes.
这里只是另外几个例子，展示了其他一些类。
So, this one is an example of find a problem and build some models.
所以，这个是找到问题并构建一些模型的一个例子。
So, these three people um, looked at Shakespearean Sonnet generation and then they considered
所以，这三个人，看着莎士比亚的十四行诗，然后他们考虑了
several different models for Shakespearean Sonnet generation and
莎士比亚十四行诗的几种不同模特
got the best results from this sort of- you'd probably can't really see all the details,
从这种方式得到最好的结果 - 你可能无法真正看到所有的细节，
but they have a sort of a mixture of word level and
但他们有一种单词级别的混合
character level gated model that feeds into
提供的字符级门控模型
a word level LSTM and produces sonnets and the output wasn't totally bad.
一个单词级LSTM并产生十四行诗并且输出并不完全糟糕。
"Thy youth's time and face his form shall cover.
“你的青年时间和面对他的形式将涵盖。
Now all fresh beauty my love there.
现在我所有的新鲜美丽都在那里。
Will ever time to greet forget each like ever decease,
将永远的时间打招呼忘记每一个像死亡一样，
but in a- in a best at worship his glory die."
但在最好的敬拜中，他的荣耀会消亡。“
Okay. It's maybe not perfect,
好的。它可能不完美，
[LAUGHTER] but it sort of sounds like a Shakespearean sonnet.
[笑声]但听起来有点像莎士比亚的十四行诗。
Um, okay.
嗯，好的。
Yeah. So, I showed you that one already.
是啊。所以，我已经向你展示了那个。
Um, here's, um, an example of someone who designed a different kind of network,
嗯，这是，嗯，一个设计不同类型网络的人的例子，
and this was a project that came out of this class that was then continued with,
这是一个来自这个课程的项目，然后继续，
and the- they got a conference paper out of it,
他们从中得到了一份会议文件，
the ICLR 2017 paper.
ICLR 2017论文。
So, this was looking at doing a better job at building a neural language model.
因此，这是为了更好地构建神经语言模型。
And essentially, they had two ideas,
基本上，他们有两个想法，
both of which seem useful for building better neural language models.
这两者似乎都有助于构建更好的神经语言模型。
And so, one is that in the stuff that we've presented so far,
所以，一个是我们到目前为止提出的东西，
whether it was the early word vectors,
是否是早期的单词向量，
or what Abby presented last week in the neural language model,
或Abby上周在神经语言模型中提出的内容，
there are effectively two vectors for each word: there's one for the word encoding
每个单词实际上有两个向量：有一个用于单词编码
on the input and then when you have the softmax on the other side effectively,
在输入上然后当你有效地在另一边有softmax时，
the rows of that matrix that go into the softmax are also
进入softmax的那个矩阵的行也是
word vectors for determining how likely you are to produce different words.
单词向量，用于确定您生成不同单词的可能性。
And so, um, these two people had the idea that maybe if we actually in the model
所以，嗯，这两个人的想法是，如果我们真的在模型中
tied those two word ve- vectors together that would help and produce a better model and,
将这两个词组合在一起，这将有助于产生更好的模型，
um, and so this was actually done
嗯，所以这实际上已经完成了
several years ago when that was a novel idea which hadn't actually been done.
几年前，那是一个实际上没有做过的新想法。
So, this was done in the 2016 class,
所以，这是在2016年的课程中完成的，
and then they had this second idea which was,
然后他们有了第二个想法，
well maybe doing the kind of,
好吧也许做那种，
cross entropy one, zero,
交叉熵一，零，
sort of you look at the correct word that you are meant to
你有没有看到你想要的正确单词
produce and sort of work out a loss based on that.
在此基础上产生和分类损失。
Maybe that's not very good because you don't get
也许这不是很好，因为你没有得到
partial points if you produce a different word that's semantically similar.
如果您生成一个语义相似的不同单词，则为分数点。
And so, that they had this idea that they could use
所以，他们有这个想法，他们可以使用
word vector similarity and then you'd be giving a score for any word that was
单词矢量相似度然后你会得到任何单词的分数
produced next based on how similar it was
根据它的相似程度制作下一个
according to word vector similarity to the word that you are
根据单词矢量与你所说的单词相似
meant to produce next and that was also
意味着生产下一个，也是
a useful idea that they're able to produce improved language models with.
一个有用的想法，他们能够生成改进的语言模型。
So, that was a cool project.
所以，这是一个很酷的项目。
Um, here's an example of, um,
嗯，这是一个例子，嗯，
somebody from last year,
去年有人，
um, who did an analysis project.
嗯，谁做了一个分析项目。
So, their idea was,
所以，他们的想法是，
um, that they- well,
嗯，他们 - 好吧，
they were going to, um,
他们要去，嗯，
evaluate on some task,
评估一些任务，
they actually did several tasks, um,
他们实际上完成了几项任务，嗯，
word similarity, analogy, and the SQuAD,
单词相似度，类比和SQuAD，
um, question answering system.
嗯，问答系统。
But the question was, okay,
但问题是，好吧，
a lot of neural network models are big and so aren't very suitable for phones, um,
很多神经网络模型很大，所以不太适合手机，嗯，
could we get away with compressing the models a lot so that rather than having doubles,
我们能不能轻易地压缩模型，而不是双打，
or 32-bit floats, or even 16-bit floats,
或32位浮点数，甚至16位浮点数，
that are now used quite a bit in neural networks, could we,
我们现在在神经网络中使用了相当多的东西，
um, compress a lot more and quantize, um,
嗯，压缩更多，量化，嗯，
numeric values so that we can only be, say,
数值，以便我们只能，比方说，
using two bits fo- per parameter so they'll literally need four bits per parameter?
使用两位参数，所以每个参数需要四位？
And if you do that naively, it doesn't work.
如果你天真地这样做，它就行不通。
But if you explore some cleverer ways of doing it and see how to make things work,
但是，如果你探索一些更聪明的方法，看看如何让事情发挥作用，
you can actually get it to work, um, really well.
你真的可以让它工作，嗯，非常好。
Um, in fact, it actually seems like sometimes you can improve
嗯，实际上，有时你似乎可以改进
your performance doing this because the quantization acts as a form of regularizer.
你的表现是因为量化是一种正规化的形式。
Um, you can find lots of other projects, um, online,
嗯，你可以找到很多其他项目，嗯，在线，
if you look at the CS224n pages and you should.
如果你看看CS224n页面，你应该。
Um, okay.
嗯，好的。
So, if you want to do a final project you have to find someplace to start.
所以，如果你想做一个最终的项目，你必须找到一个可以开始的地方。
You know, one place is to start looking at papers there's
你知道，有一个地方就是开始看那些文件
online anthology of most of the NLP conference papers.
大多数NLP会议论文的在线选集。
You can look at M- ML conferences have lots of relevant papers as well.
你可以看看M-ML会议也有很多相关论文。
You can look at past CS224n papers that cover lots of topics.
您可以查看过去涵盖大量主题的CS224n论文。
Um, though, you know, I- I sugge- don't also forget, um,
嗯，你知道，我 - 我建议 - 不要忘了，嗯，
the advice down the bottom, um,
最底层的建议，嗯，
which is look for an interesting problem in the world.
这是寻找世界上一个有趣的问题。
Um, so, our Stanford's CS emeritus professor
嗯，我们斯坦福大学的CS退休教授
Ed Feigenbaum likes to quote the advice of his,
Ed Feigenbaum喜欢引用他的建议，
um, advisor, Herb Simon, um,
嗯，顾问，Herb Simon，嗯，
of "If you see a research area where many people are working, go somewhere else."
“如果你看到很多人都在工作的研究区域，那么去其他地方。”
Um, well, you know,
嗯，嗯，你知道，
in the context of this class don't go so far away that you're not using
在这个课程的上下文中，你没有使用过这么远的地方
neural networks or NLP because that won't work for project for this class.
神经网络或NLP，因为这不适用于这个类的项目。
But, you know, nevertheless, I mean,
但是，你知道，不过，我的意思是，
in some sense it's a bad strategy of
从某种意义上说，这是一个糟糕的策略
saying let's look at all the papers that were published last year,
说让我们看看去年发表的所有论文，
and let's wo- start working on one of their problems,
让我们开始解决他们的一个问题，
or lots of people are working on question-answering, I'll do it too.
或许多人正在进行问答，我也会这样做。
You know, there are lots of interesting different problems
你知道，有很多有趣的不同问题
in the world and if you know of some, you know,
在世界上如果你知道一些，你知道，
cool website that somehow does something interesting related to language,
很酷的网站，以某种方式做一些有趣的语言，
you know, maybe you can make a final project out of that.
你知道，也许你可以做出最后的项目。
Um, other ways to find final projects.
嗯，寻找最终项目的其他方法。
Um, so the person who's first put together most of
嗯，所以第一次把大部分人放在一起的人
the CS231n content was And- Andrej Karpathy, um,
CS231n的内容是And- Andrej Karpathy，嗯，
who now works at Tesla and among his other- things
谁现在在特斯拉工作，以及他的其他事情
he did for the world he put together this site Arxiv Sanity Preserver, um,
他为这个网站Arxiv Sanity Preserver整理了这个世界，嗯，
which is a way to find online archive papers which is
这是一种查找在线档案文件的方法
a major pre-print server and if you say a few papers you're interested in,
一个主要的预打印服务器，如果你说一些你感兴趣的论文，
it'll show you other papers that you're interested in.
它会告诉你其他你感兴趣的论文。
It'll show you papers that are currently trending.
它将向您展示目前趋势的论文。
So, that can be a good way to look.
所以，这可能是一个好看的方式。
Um, if you think it'd be just good to be in
嗯，如果你觉得入住会很好
some competition where you're wanting to
你想要的一些比赛
build a system that's better than other people's,
建立一个比其他人更好的系统，
um, you can look at leaderboards for various tasks.
嗯，你可以看看各种任务的排行榜。
So, there's this brand new site which is pretty good though
所以，这个全新的网站虽然相当不错
not completely error free and correct, of
不完全没有错误和正确的
paperswithcode.com, and it collects a whole lot of
paperswithcode.com，它收集了很多
leaderboards for a whole lot of machine learning tasks including tons of language ones.
用于大量机器学习任务的排行榜，包括大量语言学习任务。
So, it gives leaderboards for question answering,
因此，它提供了问答的排行榜，
machine translation, named entity recognition,
机器翻译，命名实体识别，
language modeling, part of speech tagging.
语言建模，词性标注。
All sorts of tasks you can find there,
你可以在那里找到各种各样的任务，
and find out what the current states of the art and datasets are.
并找出当前的技术和数据集的状态。
Okay. Um, so, you know,
好的。嗯，你知道，
different projects are different,
不同的项目是不同的，
but often for a lot of projects the things you need to be making sure of is
但通常对于很多项目来说，你需要确定的是
that something that you can get a decent amount of data about so you can train a model.
你可以获得大量数据的东西，这样你就可以训练模型。
It's a feasible task,
这是一项可行的任务，
it's not so enormous you can't possibly do it in four weeks.
它不是那么庞大，你不可能在四周内完成它。
Um, you'll want to have some evaluation metric and
嗯，你会想要一些评估指标和
normally for deep learning you have to have-
通常对于深度学习，你必须 -
even if you hope to do some human evaluation,
即使你希望做一些人的评价，
as well, you have to have some automatic evaluation metric.
同样，你必须有一些自动评估指标。
Because unless there's just some code that you can run
因为除非只有一些代码可以运行
that gives you a score for how well you're doing,
这可以让你得到你的表现，
then unless you have that,
那么除非你有，
you just sort of can't do the deep learning trick of saying, "Okay,
你只是不能做深刻的学习伎俩说：“好的，
let's, um, do backpropagation to optimize our scores according to this metric."
让我们根据这个指标进行反向传播以优化我们的分数。“
And pretty much you'll want to do that to be able to do neural network optimization.
而且你几乎要做到这一点才能进行神经网络优化。
Um, and we do require that there is an important part of NLP in your class project.
嗯，我们确实要求你的班级项目中有一个NLP的重要部分。
I mean, it doesn't have to be only thing,
我的意思是，它不一定是唯一的东西，
you can be doing reinforcement learning as well,
你也可以做强化学习，
or you could do images to caption, say you're
或者你可以做图片来标题，说你是
doing joint vision and NLP,
做联合视力和NLP，
but there has to be NLP in it.
但必须有NLP。
Okay. Ah, last bit before I get back onto the content from last week.
好的。啊，在我回到上周的内容之前的最后一点。
Ah, so, something that you'll need to do is have data for your project.
啊，那么，你需要做的就是为你的项目提供数据。
Um, so some people collect their own data for a project and, you know,
嗯，所以有些人为项目收集自己的数据，你知道，
it's not impossible to collect your own data
收集您自己的数据并非不可能
especially if there's something you can do with unsupervised data.
特别是如果您可以使用无监督数据进行操作。
You might be able to get it by just sort of crawling an interesting website.
你可以通过抓取一个有趣的网站来获得它。
You can annotate a small amount of data yourself.
您可以自己注释少量数据。
If you have any site that has some kind of, you know,
如果你有任何类型的网站，你知道，
ratings annotation stars on it,
评级标注明星，
you can treat those as a form of, ah, annotation.
你可以把它当作一种形式啊，注释。
Right? So, if you want to predict something like, um, you know,
对？所以，如果你想预测类似的东西，嗯，你知道，
which descriptions on product review websites
产品评论网站上的哪些描述
or which reviews on product review websites do people like?
人们喜欢哪些产品评论网站的评论？
Well, they get star ratings at the bottom from people and
好吧，他们从人们那里获得了最低评级
then you can try and fit to that as your supervision.
那么你可以尝试并适合你的监督。
Um, sometimes people have data from an existing project for a company.
嗯，有时人们拥有公司现有项目的数据。
You can use that.
你可以用它。
But nevertheless for most people, um,
但对大多数人来说，嗯，
given that classes are short and things like that,
鉴于课程很短，有类似的东西，
the practical thing to do is use
实际的事情是使用
an existing curated dataset that's been built by previous researchers.
现有的策划数据集，由以前的研究人员构建。
That normally gives you a fast start and lets you get to work building models, um,
这通常会让你快速入门，让你开始建立模型，嗯，
there's obvious prior work,
以前有明显的工作，
there are baselines and previous systems
有基线和以前的系统
that you can compare your performance on, et cetera.
你可以比较你的表现，等等。
Okay. Um, so, where can you find data?
好的。嗯，那么，你在哪里可以找到数据？
I'll just mention a couple of places here and there are lots more.
我会在这里提到几个地方，还有更多。
So, traditionally the biggest source of
所以，传统上是最大的来源
linguistic data used by academics was this place called
学术界使用的语言数据就是这个地方
the Linguistic Data Consortium and they have lots of
语言数据联盟，他们有很多
datasets for treebanks and named entities and coreference,
树库和命名实体和共同参照的数据集，
parallel machine, translation data,
并行机，翻译数据，
et cetera, et cetera.
等等。
And so, um, the Linguistic Data Consortium licenses their data,
所以，嗯，Linguistic Data Consortium授权他们的数据，
Stanford pays that license so you can use any of it.
斯坦福支付该许可证，因此您可以使用它。
Um, but if you want to use it, um,
嗯，但如果你想用它，嗯，
you go to that, um, linguistics.stanford.edu page.
你去那，嗯，linguistics.stanford.edu页面。
And there's a sign-up, um, ah,
有一个注册，嗯，啊，
piece on how to sign up where you basically, um, say,
关于如何在基本上注册的地方，嗯，说，
"I will use this data only for
“我将仅使用此数据
good Stanford purposes and not as the basis of my startup."
良好的斯坦福目的，而不是我的创业基础。“
And, um, then you can have access to that data
而且，嗯，那么你可以访问这些数据
and it can be made available by NFS or otherwise.
它可以通过NFS或其他方式提供。
Um, but as time has gone by,
嗯，但随着时间的推移，
there's a ton of curated NLP data that's available on various websites.
有很多策划的NLP数据可以在各种网站上找到。
In fact, if anything the problem is it's just sort of
事实上，如果有任何问题，那就是它
spread over the web and that's sort of hard to find different things.
传播到网络上，这很难找到不同的东西。
But there are some, some sites that have a lot of data for various purposes.
但是有些网站有很多用于各种目的的数据。
So, anything related to machine translation or just parallel,
所以，任何与机器翻译相关的东西或者只是平行的
um, data across different languages.
嗯，不同语言的数据。
The statistical MT statmt.org site has a great amount of
统计MT statmt.org网站有很多
data and that organization runs shared tasks every year,
数据和该组织每年运行共享任务，
the Workshop on Machine Translation,
机器翻译研讨会，
WMT which Abby already mentioned in her class.
Abby已经在她的课堂上提到的WMT。
And they've got datasets that we use for
他们有我们用于的数据集
those tasks and then there are leaderboards for those tasks.
那些任务，然后有这些任务的排行榜。
And you can find data for that.
你可以找到相关的数据。
Um, if you thought dependency parsing was cool, um,
嗯，如果你认为依赖解析很酷，嗯，
there's the Universal Dependencies site which has parallel, not parallel site,
Universal Dependencies网站有并行而非并行网站，
which has treebanks in the same annotation scheme for
其中有相同注释方案的树库
about 60 different languages and you can work on
大约60种不同的语言，你可以继续工作
parsers for different languages and things like that.
解析器用于不同的语言和类似的东西。
Um, I'm not gonna bore you with going through all of them but, you know,
嗯，我不会厌倦你经历所有这些，但是，你知道，
there are just tons and tons of other datasets that
只有吨和其他数据集
Facebook has released datasets, Google's released datasets,
Facebook发布了数据集，Google发布的数据集，
I said Stanford have released several other datasets including
我说斯坦福已经发布了其他几个数据集，包括
the Stanford Sentiment Treebank and the Stanford Na- Natural Language, um,
Stanford Sentiment Treebank和Stanford Na- Natural Language，嗯，
Inference corpus, uh, new question-answering datasets and
推理语料库，呃，新的问答数据集和
including HotPotQA and conversational question answering.
包括HotPotQA和会话问题解答。
Other groups at different universities have released datasets.
不同大学的其他小组已经发布了数据集。
There are just tons of them.
它们只有很多。
You can find data on sites like Kaggle where it has machine-learning competitions.
您可以在像Kaggle这样的机器学习比赛的网站上找到数据。
There are sites with lists of datasets.
有些站点包含数据集列表。
You can look at research papers and see what datasets they used.
您可以查看研究论文并查看他们使用的数据集。
And of course, you can ask the course staff or on Piazza
当然，您可以询问课程工作人员或广场
to try and find suitable datasets for a project.
尝试为项目找到合适的数据集。
Okay. Um, so that's a fair bit about
好的。嗯，所以这是一个相当的
the projects that I've got a bit more to say later about doing projects.
我后来有关项目的更多话题。
Does anyone have any questions up until now on projects?
到目前为止，有没有人对项目有任何疑问？
Okay. Um, well, so now we're gonna sort of, um,
好的。嗯，好吧，现在我们就好了，嗯，
flip a switch in our brains and go back and have one more look,
翻转我们大脑中的开关然后再回过头来看看，
um, at gated recurrent units,
嗯，在门控经常性单位，
um, and what happens and what they mean.
嗯，会发生什么以及他们的意思。
Um, and, you know,
嗯，你知道，
this is sort of,
这有点像，
sort of the same material that Abby presented,
与Abby提供的相同材料，
presented a little bit differently but, you know,
提出了一点点不同，但是，你知道，
I hope it might just sort of give one more way of
我希望它可能只是提供一种方式
sort of thinking a bit about what's happening about
想一想有关正在发生的事情
these gated recurrent units and why they might be doing
这些门控的经常性单位以及他们为什么这样做
something useful and what are the alternatives to them.
一些有用的东西，它们的替代品是什么。
So, if you remember the problem we started with is that we
所以，如果你还记得我们开始的问题就是我们
wanted to understand sort of derivatives backward in time.
想要及时了解各种衍生品。
And so, the idea of that is well,
所以，这个想法很好，
if we twiddle this a little bit at time T,
如果我们在时间T稍微旋转一下，
how much effect is that going to have so we make some adjustment here.
会有多大的影响，所以我们在这里做一些调整。
How much effect is that going to have n time steps later?
有多少时间后会有n个时间步骤？
Um, and well, we sort of looked at the derivatives and we sort of saw we got these,
嗯，好吧，我们看看衍生品，我们看到我们得到了这些，
um, terms for each successive time step.
嗯，每个连续时间步的术语。
And so as Abby discussed the problem is that for the derivatives that we got,
因此，Abby讨论的问题是，对于我们得到的衍生物，
we kind of got this matrix form for each time step.
我们为每个时间步都得到了这种矩阵形式。
And so that if we're going through a lot of time steps,
因此，如果我们经历了很多时间步骤，
we got a lot of matrix multiplies and as the result of those matrix multiplies,
我们得到了很多矩阵乘法，并且作为矩阵乘法的结果，
pretty much either things disappeared down to
几乎任何事情都消失了
zero or exploded upward depending on what was in the matrix.
零或向上爆炸取决于矩阵中的内容。
And so that- and so that's sort of means we,
所以 - 这就是我们的意思，
When the gradient goes to zero,
当梯度变为零时，
we kind of can't know what's happening there.
我们有点不知道那里发生了什么。
Whether there isn't any conditioning or just we can't measure it.
是否没有任何条件或只是我们无法衡量它。
And so that's sort of made people think that maybe this naive, um,
所以这让人们觉得这可能是天真的，嗯，
recurrent neural network transition function just isn't a good one to use.
递归神经网络转换功能只是不是一个好用的。
And that sort of leads into these ideas of gated recurrent units.
这种导致了门控复发单元的这些想法。
Right? Because if we have
对？因为如果我们有
the simple recurrent neural network where we're
我们所在的简单的递归神经网络
sort of feeding forward for each step in time.
为每个步骤及时前进。
Well, what happens is when we backpropagate.
那么，当我们反向传播时会发生什么。
We have to backpropagate through
我们必须反过来传播
every intermediate node and that's where we sort of have our gradients disappear.
每个中间节点，这就是我们的渐变消失的地方。
And so an idea of how you could fix that is to say well,
因此，如何解决这个问题的想法就是说，
suppose we just put in direct connections that were longer distance, um,
假设我们只是建立了更长距离的直接连接，嗯，
then we'd also get direct backpropagation signal
那么我们也会得到直接的反向传播信号
and so then we wouldn't have this same problem of vanishing gradients.
所以我们就不会有同样消失渐变的问题。
And effectively, we've sort of looked at two ways in which you can achieve that effect.
实际上，我们有两种方法可以实现这种效果。
Because one way of you can achieve that effect which Abby looked at
因为你的一种方式可以达到Abby所看到的那种效果
in the end part of the last lecture was this idea of attention.
在上一次讲座的最后部分是这种关注的想法。
So, when you've got attention,
所以，当你得到关注时，
you're actually are creating these shortcut connections,
你实际上是在创建这些快捷方式连接，
oops, they're the blue ones, um,
哎呀，他们是蓝色的，嗯，
from every time step and using it to calculate an attention distribution.
从每个时间步骤并使用它来计算注意力分布。
But the way the attention was done that we looked at,
但是我们看到了注意力的方式，
it was sort of mushing together all previous time steps into some kind of an average.
它有点像以前的所有步骤一样拼凑成某种平均值。
But the idea of the gated recurrent units is in some sense we want to
但是在某种意义上我们想要的是门控循环单元的想法
achieve this same kind of ability to have shortcut connections.
实现这种具有快捷连接的能力。
But we want to do it in
但是我们想要这样做
a more controlled and adaptive fashion where we still do remember the position of things.
一种更加控制和适应性的方式，我们仍然记得事物的位置。
So, how can we create an adaptive shortcut connection?
那么，我们如何创建自适应快捷方式连接呢？
And so that's, um,
那就是，嗯，
what we start to do with the gates that are put into a gated recurrent network.
我们开始做的是进入门控循环网络的门。
So, if- so first off we sort of say let's have
所以，如果首先我们有点说我们有
a candidate update which is exactly the same
候选人更新完全相同
as the one that's used in a simple recurrent neural network.
作为在简单的递归神经网络中使用的那个。
But what we can do is add a gate.
但我们能做的就是增加一个门。
And so, the gate will calculate a value from zero to one.
因此，门将计算从零到一的值。
And so what we're going to do here is mix together
所以我们在这里要做的就是混合在一起
using our candidate update which is just like
使用我们的候选更新就像
a simple recurrent neural network which will be then mixed together with simply
一个简单的递归神经网络，然后简单地混合在一起
directly carrying forward the hidden state from the previous time step.
从前一个时间步骤直接转发隐藏状态。
So, once we're doing that we are sort of then adaptively-
所以，一旦我们这样做，我们就会适应性地 -
we're adaptively partly using a computation from one time step back,
我们自适应地部分使用一次性计算，
um, done as a recurrent neural network.
嗯，作为一个递归的神经网络。
And we're partly just inheriting the,
我们部分只是继承了，
we're just part- sorry, we're partly inheriting
我们只是对不起，我们部分继承了
the hidden state from the previous time step.
上一个时间步的隐藏状态。
So, it's sort of like a shortcut connection but we're waiting as to
所以，它有点像快捷键，但我们还在等待
how much we're short cutting and how much we're doing our computation.
我们做多少短切以及我们在做多少计算。
And we control that adaptive choice by using a calculation to set the gate.
我们通过使用计算设置门来控制自适应选择。
And we do that with a sigmoid, um,
我们用sigmoid做到这一点，嗯，
computed over the import and the hidden- previous hidden state and using it again,
计算导入和隐藏 - 先前隐藏状态并再次使用它，
an equation kind of like a simple recurrent neural network.
一个类似于简单的递归神经网络的方程式。
Okay. Um, but, you know,
好的。嗯，但是，你知道，
if you wanted to go a bit further than that,
如果你想要比这更进一步，
um, you could think well,
嗯，你可以好好想想，
maybe sometimes we sort of might actually
也许有时候我们可能真的
just want to get rid of the stuff that was in the past.
只是想摆脱过去的东西。
That maybe the stuff in the past sometimes becomes irrelevant, like,
也许过去的东西有时会变得无关紧要，比如，
maybe sometimes we start a new sentence or a new
也许有时我们会开一个新句子或一个新句子
thought and we just want to get rid of the stuff that's in the past.
我想，我们只是想摆脱过去的东西。
And so, that can lead into this idea of having a second gate,
所以，这可以导致这个有第二道门的想法，
a reset gate and so the reset gate calculates a value from 0 to 1, um,
复位门，因此复位门计算0到1的值，嗯，
just like the other gates,
就像其他门一样
and then we're doing this element wise dot-product between
然后我们正在做这个元素明智的点积之间
the reset gate and the previous hidden state and that's then sort of saying well,
重置门和之前的隐藏状态，然后说得好，
maybe we want to keep some parts of what was stored
也许我们想保留存储的部分内容
previously and some parts that we now want to throw away.
以前和我们现在想扔掉的一些部分。
And so we put that into the model as a second gate.
因此我们将其作为第二道门放入模型中。
Um, and so an interesting way to think about that is to sort of think
嗯，这是一个有趣的思考方式就是思考
about this as if this recurrent neural network is like
关于这就像这个反复出现的神经网络一样
a little tiny computer as the kind of little tiny computers you
一台小小的电脑就像你那种小小的电脑
might do in a sort of simple architecture class and if you think about it that way,
可能会在一个简单的架构类中做，如果你这样思考，
um, for the basic simple recurrent neural network
嗯，对于基本的简单递归神经网络
the way the tiny computer works is that you've got a bank of registers h,
微型计算机的工作方式是你有一组寄存器h，
your hidden state, and at each time step you have to
你隐藏的状态，你必须在每一步
read- whoops, at each time step you have to read the entirety of your bank of registers,
读 - 哎呀，在每个时间步，你必须阅读你的整个寄存器组，
you do some computation and then you write
你做一些计算，然后你写
the entirety of your bank of registers and, you know,
您的整个注册银行，你知道，
if in terms of thinking about computer architecture,
如果在考虑计算机体系结构方面，
that sounds like a pretty bad way to implement a simple computer.
这听起来像是一种实现简单计算机的糟糕方式。
Um, so precisely what a gated recurrent unit is doing is saying,
嗯，正如门控经常性单位正在做的那样，
"Well, maybe we can have a slightly more sophisticated little baby computer."
“好吧，也许我们可以拥有一台稍微复杂的小型婴儿电脑。”
Instead of that, we could select a subset of the registers that we want to read.
而不是那样，我们可以选择我们想要读取的寄存器的子集。
And so, the reset gate can control that because it can say,
因此，重置门可以控制，因为它可以说，
"We'll just ignore a bunch of the other registers."
“我们只会忽略其他一些寄存器。”
Um, it then will compute a new value based on just these, um,
嗯，它会根据这些来计算一个新值，嗯，
stored registers and then the update gate which is also adaptive can say, "Well,
存储寄存器然后更新门也是自适应的可以说，“嗯，
I want you to write
我要你写
some registers but the rest of the registers will just keep their previous value."
一些寄存器，但其余的寄存器只会保留它们以前的值。“
That seems a useful idea to have in a computer.
这在计算机中似乎是一个有用的想法。
And so, that's what we're doing here.
所以，这就是我们在这里所做的。
And so, this model here is, um,
所以，这个模型是，嗯，
what was- Abby presented second as the gated recurrent unit.
是什么 - 艾比作为门控复发单位排名第二。
So, this is sort of a much more realistic model
所以，这是一种更加现实的模型
and it sort of in some sense overlaps with the ideas of attention.
它在某种意义上与注意力的想法重叠。
Okay. Um, so gated recurrent units are actually a quite new model.
好的。嗯，如此门控的经常性单位实际上是一个相当新的模型。
Um, the model that was done way earlier and has had huge impact
嗯，这种模式早先做得很好并且产生了巨大的影响
is these LSTM long short-term memory units and they are a bit more complex.
是这些LSTM长期短期内存单元，它们有点复杂。
Um, but, you know,
嗯，但是，你知道，
a lot of it is sort of the same, right?
很多都是一样的，对吧？
So, the hidden state of
所以，隐藏的状态
a gated recurrent unit is kind of equivalent to the cell of the LSTM.
门控循环单元类似于LSTM的单元。
So, both of them are using the same idea of summing together,
所以，他们俩都在使用相同的概念，
a mixture of just directly interpret- directly inheriting
直接解释 - 直接继承的混合物
what you had from the previous time step together with, um,
你从上一次的步骤中得到了什么，嗯，
something that you've calculated for the current time step and the way you count-
您为当前时间步骤计算的内容以及您计算的方式 -
calculate it for the current time step is exactly the same in both cases.
计算当前时间步长在两种情况下完全相同。
Whoops, sorry. Both cases again that you're calculating
哎呀，抱歉。这两种情况都是你在计算的
the current update using this sort of simple RNN equation.
使用这种简单的RNN方程进行的当前更新。
So, those parts are exactly the same.
所以，那些部分是完全一样的。
Um, but the LSTM is a little bit more complicated.
嗯，但LSTM有点复杂。
It now has three gates, um,
它现在有三个门，嗯，
and it's got this extra, um,
它有额外的，嗯，
hidden state that's then worked out with a bit more complexity.
隐藏的状态，然后更复杂一点。
So, in terms of my LSTM picture, you know,
那么，就我的LSTM图片而言，你知道，
the LSTM picture looks as if you sort of pull apart all of its math pretty
LSTM图片看起来好像你把它的所有数学分开了
complex but so there are three gates so that you can forget or ignore everything.
复杂，但所以有三个门，所以你可以忘记或忽略一切。
So, you can forget or ignore the input,
所以，你可以忘记或忽略输入，
you can forget or ignore parts of
你可以忘记或忽略部分内容
your previous hidden state and you can forget or ignore parts of the cell
你之前隐藏的状态，你可以忘记或忽略单元格的一部分
when calculating the output and each of these
在计算输出和每个输出时
is produce- when I say forget or ignore parts of,
生产 - 当我说忘记或忽略部分，
what that's meaning is you're calculating a vector which is then going to be element-wise
这是什么意思，你正在计算一个矢量，然后这个矢量将是元素方面的
multiplied by the import of the previous hidden state or the cell.
乘以前一个隐藏状态或单元格的导入。
And so, that's why you have this effective now an addressable bank of
所以，这就是为什么你现在这个有效的可解决的银行
registers where you can use some of them but not others of them.
注册你可以使用其中一些而不是其他的。
Okay. So, the bottom part of the LSTM is just
好的。所以，LSTM的底部只是
like a simpler simple recurrent neural network,
像一个简单的简单递归神经网络，
um, which then calculates,
嗯，然后计算，
um, a candidate update.
嗯，候选人更新。
And so, for both of the GRU and the LSTM the real secret is
因此，对于GRU和LSTM来说，真正的秘密就是
that rather than just keeping on multiplying
而不是仅仅继续增加
stuff what you do is you add two things together.
你做的是你把两件事加在一起。
Um, and so this adding is why you don't
嗯，所以这个添加就是你不这样做的原因
get the same vanishing gradient evil effects because you're calculating a
获得相同的消失梯度邪恶效果，因为你正在计算一个
new candidate update and you're adding it to stuff that was
新的候选人更新，你将它添加到那些东西
previously in the cell and that gives you
以前在单元格中，它给你
a simple gradient when you backpropagate that- that you have
一个简单的渐变，当你反向传播 - 你有
direct linear connection between the cell at time t and the cell at time t minus one.
在时间t的细胞和时间t的细胞减去1之间的直接线性连接。
And so, really that simple addition there is sort of
所以，真的那么简单的补充就有了
the secret of most of the power of LSTMs and
LSTM和LSTM的大部分力量的秘密
this same idea of adding two things together has also been a
将两个东西放在一起的同样想法也是一个
secret of many of the other advances in deep learning recently.
最近深度学习的许多其他进展的秘密。
So, envision in the last couple of years the sort of standard model
因此，在过去几年中设想了那种标准模型
that everybody uses as ResNets, residual networks and they use
每个人都使用Resnet，剩余网络和他们使用
exactly the same secret of allowing these adaptive updates where you add
在你添加的地方允许这些自适应更新的秘诀完全相同
together a current layer's value with directly inheriting a value from the layer below.
将当前图层的值与下面的图层中的值直接继承在一起。
Um, other things that use similar ideas are things like highway networks and so on.
嗯，其他使用类似想法的东西都是高速公路网等等。
So, that's proven to be an extremely powerful idea.
所以，这被证明是一个非常强大的想法。
Um, the LSTM is slightly different from
嗯，LSTM略有不同
the GRU because when we look back at its equations
GRU，因为当我们回顾它的方程时
that the- the GRU kind of does a linear mixture where you have one gate value,
那个 -  GRU类型是一个线性混合物，你有一个门值，
UT, and one minus UT,
UT，一个减去UT，
where the LSTM adds values controlled by two different gates,
LSTM增加由两个不同门控制的值，
a forget gate, and an input gate.
忘记门和输入门。
Theoretically, having the adding of
理论上，有添加
two separate gates rather than than a mixture is theoretically more powerful.
理论上，两个单独的门而不是混合物更强大。
Um, depending on the application,
嗯，取决于应用，
sometimes it doesn't seem to make much difference, um,
有时似乎并没有多大区别，嗯，
but there's definitely a theoretical advantage to the LSTM there.
但那里的LSTM肯定有理论上的优势。
Okay. Um, just, I hope that's maybe a little bit more helpful to have seen those again,
好的。嗯，只是，我希望再次见到这些可能会更有帮助，
um, any questions on gated recurrent units?
嗯，关于门控经常性单位的任何问题？
Still look confusing?
仍然看起来令人困惑？
I think it's useful to have some kind of idea as to why the people come up with
我认为对于人们想出的原因有一些想法是有用的
these things and why do they make sense but,
这些东西，为什么它们有意义，但是，
you know, nevertheless, the reality is in the sort of era of
但是，你知道，现实正处于那种时代
2015 plus any deep learning package you use whether it's PyTorch,
2015年加上您使用的任何深度学习包，无论是PyTorch，
TensorFlow, MXNet whatever, you know,
TensorFlow，MXNet无论如何，你知道，
it just comes with LSTM and GRUs and you don't have to program your own.
它只是附带LSTM和GRU，你不必自己编程。
In fact, you're at disadvantage if you
事实上，如果你处于劣势
program your own because if you are using the built-in one,
自己编程，因为如果你使用内置的，
it's using an efficient CUDA kernel from
它使用的是高效的CUDA内核
Nvidia whereas your custom built one won't and/or run three times slower.
Nvidia，而你定制的一个不会和/或运行速度慢三倍。
Um, so, you know, essentially don't have to know how to do it,
嗯，你知道，基本上不必知道怎么做，
you can just take the attitude that an LSTM is just like
你可以采取LSTM就像的态度
a fancy recurrent network which will be easier to train and that's true.
一个花哨的经常性网络，这将更容易训练，这是真的。
Um, but you know, these kind of architectural ideas have actually been
嗯，但是你知道，这些建筑思想实际上已经存在
central to most of the big advances that have come in deep learning in the last couple of years,
在过去几年中深入学习的大部分进步的核心，
so there's actually good to have an ID,
所以有一个ID真的很好，
to have some sense of what were
了解一下是什么
these important ideas that made everything so much better because they had
这些重要的想法使得一切都变得更好，因为他们拥有
the same kind of component building blocks you might also want
您可能也想要的相同类型的组件构建块
to use in custom models that you design for yourself.
用于您自己设计的自定义模型。
Okay, two bits of machine translation.
好的，两位机器翻译。
Um, so a bit of machine translation that we
嗯，我们有点机器翻译
sort of didn't cover next week but lots of people have been seeing
下周没有报道，但很多人都看到了
and getting confused by in the assignments so I thought I'd explain
并且在作业中感到困惑，所以我想我会解释
a bit about is UNKs and explain where do UNKs
有点关于UNK并解释UNK在哪里
come from and why are there UNKs and the reason why
来自，为什么有UNKs和原因
there are UNKs is effectively kind of for efficiency reasons.
因为效率原因，UNK实际上是有点类的。
So, if you sort of think about producing output in a neural machine translation system
所以，如果你考虑在神经机器翻译系统中产生输出
and really this is the same as producing output
这真的和产量一样
in any natural, neural natural language generation system,
在任何自然的神经自然语言生成系统中，
so that's really the same for neural language model, um,
对于神经语言模型来说真的是一样的，嗯，
that if you have a very large output vocabulary is just a expensive operation.
如果你有一个非常大的输出词汇只是一个昂贵的操作。
So you have a big matrix of softmax parameters where you have a row for every word, um,
所以你有一个很大的softmax参数矩阵，每个字都有一行，嗯，
and then you have what,
然后你有什么，
[NOISE] then we have an animation that is not working for me.
[NOISE]然后我们有一个不适合我的动画。
Oh, all right there, there we go.
哦，好吧，我们去吧。
Um, so then we have some hidden state that we've
嗯，那么我们就有一些隐藏的状态
calculated in our recurrent neural network.
在我们的递归神经网络中计算。
And so, what we gonna do is sort of multiply, um,
所以，我们要做的就是繁殖，嗯，
that vector by every row of the matrix,
矩阵的每一行的那个向量，
put it through a softmax and then get probabilities without putting every word.
把它通过softmax，然后获得概率，而不是把每一个字。
Um, and you know,
嗯，你知道，
this seems pretty simple but the problem is that
这似乎很简单，但问题是
to the extent that you have a humongous vocabulary here,
如果你在这里有一个庞大的词汇，
you just have to do a humongous number of rows
你只需要做大量的行
of this multiplication and it actually turns out that
这个乘法实际上是这样的
doing this is the expensive part of
这样做是昂贵的一部分
having a neural machine translation or neural language model system, right?
有神经机器翻译或神经语言模型系统，对吧？
The LSTM might look complicated and hard to understand, but you know,
LSTM可能看起来很复杂而且难以理解，但是你知道，
it's relatively small vectors that you multiply or dot-product once,
它是一个相对较小的向量，你繁殖或点积一次，
and it's not that much work whereas if you have a huge number of words,
并没有那么多的工作，而如果你有大量的话，
this is a huge amount of work.
这是一项庞大的工作。
So, just for instance sort of for the pion- pioneering sequence to sequence,
所以，就像π-开创序列的序列一样，
um, neural machine translation system that Google first did,
嗯，谷歌第一次做的神经机器翻译系统，
they ran it on an eight GPU machine because they have lots of GPUs but
他们在八台GPU上运行它，因为它们有很多GPU但是
the way they set it up to maximize performance was of those eight GPUs,
他们设置它以最大化性能的方式是那八个GPU，
three of them were running
其中三人正在奔跑
a deep multi-layer neural sequence model and the other five GPUs,
深层多层神经序列模型和其他五个GPU，
the only thing that they were doing was calculating softmaxes because that's
他们唯一要做的就是计算softmaxes，因为那样
actually the bulk of the computation that you need to be able to do.
实际上你需要做的大部分计算。
Um, so the simplest way to make this, um,
嗯，这是最简单的方法，嗯，
computation not completely excessive is to say,
计算不完全过度就是说，
"Hey, I'll just limit the vocabulary."
“嘿，我只会限制词汇量。”
Yeah I know that you can make
是的，我知道你可以做
a million different words in English and if you look at Spanish inflections of verbs,
一百万个不同的英语单词，如果你看一下西班牙语的动词，
there are a lot of them and there's gonna be huge number of words, um,
它们中有很多，而且会有很多单词，嗯，
but maybe I can just make do with a modest vocabulary and it'll be near enough.
但也许我可以用一个适度的词汇来做，它就足够了。
Surely 50,000 common words,
肯定有5万个常用词，
I can cover a lot of stuff and so,
我可以涵盖很多东西，所以，
that was sort of the starting off point of neural machine translation that you,
那是你神经机器翻译的起点，
people use the modest vocabulary like around 50,000 words.
人们使用适当的词汇量，大约50,000字。
And well, if you do that, um,
好吧，如果你这样做，嗯，
well, then what happens is you have UNKs.
好吧，那么你会遇到UNK。
So UNK means, this is an unknown word,
所以UNK意味着，这是一个未知的词，
that's not in my vocabulary and so there are two kinds of UNKs,
那不是我的词汇，因此有两种UNK，
they can be UNKs in the source language and you know,
他们可以是源语言的UNK，你知道，
they're sort of optional because, you know,
它们是可选的，因为，你知道，
it's not actually a problem having a large source language vocabulary,
它实际上并不是一个拥有大量源语言词汇的问题，
but the fact of the matter is if you've sort of trained
但事实是，如果你有一些训练有素的话
a model on a certain amount of data,
关于一定数量的数据的模型，
there are some words you aren't going to have seen,
有一些你不会看到的词，
so you are going to have words that you just didn't
所以你会得到你刚才没有的话
see in your training data and you won't have
请参阅您的培训数据，但您不会
any pre-trained or trained word vector
任何预先训练或训练过的单词矢量
for them and you can deal with that by either just treating them as UNK,
对于他们而言，你可以通过将它们视为UNK来处理它，
so giving them a new word vector when you encounter them.
所以当你遇到它们时给它们一个新的单词向量。
But the tricky part is on the translation that you're wanting to
但棘手的部分是你想要的翻译
produce these rare words but they're not in your output vocabulary,
产生这些罕见的单词，但它们不在你的输出词汇中，
so your system is producing UNK, UNK to UNK, which is not a very good translation really.
所以你的系统正在生产UNK，UNK到UNK，这真的不是一个非常好的翻译。
Um, yeah, and so that was sort of what the first,
嗯，是的，这就是第一个，
um, machine, neural machine translation systems, um, did.
嗯，机器，神经机器翻译系统，嗯，做了。
And so, you know, obviously that's not
所以，你知道，显然不是这样
a very satisfactory state of affairs and so there's been a whole bunch of work,
一个非常令人满意的事态，所以有很多工作，
um, as to how to deal with this,
嗯，关于如何处理这个问题，
so you can use methods that allow you to deal with a larger output vocabulary,
所以你可以使用允许你处理更大输出词汇量的方法，
um, without the computation being excessive.
嗯，没有计算过多。
So one method of doing that is to have what's called a hierarchical softmax,
所以这样做的一种方法是拥有所谓的分层softmax，
so that rather than just having a huge matrix of words,
所以，而不是只有一个巨大的单词矩阵，
you sort of have a tree structure in your vocabulary
你的词汇表中有一个树形结构
so you can do calculations with hierarchical,
所以你可以用层次结构进行计算，
um, multiple small softmaxes and you can do that more quickly.
嗯，多个小的softmax，你可以更快地做到这一点。
Um, I'm not gonna go through all these exam,
嗯，我不会经历所有这些考试，
all these things in detail now,
现在所有这些细节，
I'm just sort of very quickly mentioning them and if anyone's interested, they can look.
我只是很快提到它们，如果有人感兴趣，他们可以看一下。
People have used the noise-contrastive estimation idea that we
人们已经使用了我们的噪声对比估计思想
saw with Word2vec in this context as well.
在这种情况下也看到了Word2vec。
So this is a way to get much faster training which is important,
所以这是一种获得更快速培训的方法，这很重要，
it's not really a way to solve, um,
它不是真正的解决方法，嗯，
speed at translation time but, you know,
在翻译时速度，但是，你知道，
if this means you can train your system in six hours instead of
如果这意味着您可以在六个小时内训练您的系统而不是
six days that's a big win and so that's a good technique to use.
六天这是一个巨大的胜利，所以这是一个很好的技术使用。
Um, people have done much smarter things, so really, um,
嗯，人们做了很多更聪明的事情，所以真的，嗯，
the large vocabulary problem is basically solved
大词汇问题基本解决了
now and so the kind of things that you can do is you can produce
现在，你可以做的事情是你可以生产的
subsets of your vocabulary and train on particular subsets of
你的词汇的子集和训练的特定子集
vocabulary at a time and then when you're testing,
一次是词汇，然后在你测试的时候，
you adaptively choose kind of a likely list of words that might
你可以自适应地选择一种可能的单词列表
appear in the translation of particular sentences or passages and then
出现在特定句子或段落的翻译中然后出现
you can effectively work with sort of an appropriate subset of
你可以有效地使用一些适当的子集
a vocabulary and that's sort of an efficient technique by which you can
一个词汇表，这是一种有效的技术
deal with an unlimited vocabulary but only be using
处理无限的词汇，但只能使用
a moderate sized softmax for any particular paragraph that you're translating,
对于您正在翻译的任何特定段落，适度大小的softmax，
there's a paper that talks about that method.
有一篇论文讨论了这种方法。
Um, another idea is you can use attention when you do translation,
嗯，另一个想法是你在翻译时可以使用注意力，
the idea talked about at the end of last time.
这个想法在上次结束时谈到了。
So if you have attention, that sort of means that you can,
所以如果你有注意力，那就意味着你可以，
you're pointing somewhere in the source and you
你指的是源头和你的某个地方
know what you're translating at any point in time.
知道你在任何时间点翻译的内容。
So, if that word is a rare word that's not in your vocabulary,
所以，如果这个词是一个不在你词汇中的罕见词，
there are things that you could do to deal with that.
你可以采取一些措施来解决这个问题。
I mean, firstly, if it's a rare word,
我的意思是，首先，如果这是一个罕见的词，
its translation is much more likely to be constant,
它的翻译更可能是不变的，
so you might just look it up in a dictionary or word list, um, and,
所以你可能只是在字典或单词列表中查找，嗯，和
um, stick in its translation,
嗯，坚持翻译，
sometimes it's appropriate to do other things.
有时做其他事情是合适的。
I mean, turns out that, you know,
我的意思是，事实证明，你知道，
quite a lot of things that unknown words turn out to be other things like, you know,
很多不为人知的事情变成其他事情，比如，你知道，
hexadecimal numbers, or FedEx tracking IDs,
十六进制数字或FedEx跟踪ID，
or GitHub shards, or things like that.
或GitHub分片，或类似的东西。
So for a lot of things like that,
所以对于很多这样的事情，
the right thing to do is just to copy them across.
正确的做法就是将它们复制过来。
And so, another thing that people have looked at is copying models,
所以，人们看到的另一件事是复制模型，
um, in machine translation.
嗯，机器翻译。
Okay, um, there are more ideas that you can,
好的，嗯，你可以有更多的想法，
we can get into to solve this and actually, um,
我们可以解决这个问题，实际上，嗯，
next week we're gonna start dealing with
下周我们将开始处理
some of the other ways that you could solve this, um,
你能解决这个问题的其他一些方法，嗯，
but I hope there to have given you sort of a sense of,
但是我希望有一种感觉，
um, sort of what these UNKs are about,
嗯，这些UNK的意思，
why you see them and, uh,
为什么你看到他们，呃，
that there are sort of some ways that you might
你可能有某种方式
deal with them but you're not expected to be doing that,
处理它们，但你不应该这样做，
um, for assignment four.
嗯，对于任务四。
Okay, then I just wanted to give a teeny bit more on evaluation.
好的，那么我只想更多地评估一下。
Um, so Abby said a little bit about
嗯，所以艾比说了一点
evaluation with blue and that then comes up in the assignment,
用蓝色进行评估，然后在作业中出现，
so I just thought I'd give you a little bit more context on
所以我只是觉得我会给你更多的背景信息
that since they're being quite a few questions about it.
因为他们有很多关于它的问题。
So, um, so the general context here is, you know,
所以，嗯，所以这里的一般背景是，你知道，
how do you evaluate machine translation quality and sort of to this day,
你如何评估机器翻译质量，直到今天，
if you wanted to do a first rate bang up evaluation of machine translation quality,
如果你想对机器翻译质量进行一流评估，
the way you do it is you get human beings to assess quality,
你这样做的方法是让人类评估质量，
you take translations and you send them to
你翻译并发送给他们
human beings with good bilingual skills and get them to score things.
拥有良好双语技能的人，让他们得分。
And there are two ways that are commonly used.
并且有两种常用方法。
One is sort of rating on
一种是评级
Likert scales for things like adequacy and fluency of translations,
李克特为翻译的充分性和流畅性等方面进行了扩展，
um, but another way that often works better is asking for comparative judgments.
嗯，但另一种往往更好的方法是要求比较判断。
So here are two translations of this sentence which is better, um.
所以这里有两个这句话的翻译，这是更好的，嗯。
And so that's, you know,
所以，你知道，
sort of still our gold standard of translation.
仍然是我们的翻译黄金标准。
Um, another way you can evaluate translation is
嗯，你可以评估翻译的另一种方式是
use your translations in the downstream task.
在下游任务中使用您的翻译。
So, you could say "I'm gonna build
所以，你可以说“我要建造
a cross-lingual question answering system and inside that system I'm,
一个跨语言的问答系统，在我的系统里面，
gonna use machine translation.
要用机器翻译。
I'm gonna translate the questions um,
我要翻译你的问题，
and then try and match them against the documents.
然后尝试将它们与文档进行匹配。
Um, and then my score will be how good my question answering system is,
嗯，然后我的分数将是我的问答系统有多好，
and so the machine translation system is better
所以机器翻译系统更好
if my question-answering score um, goes up."
如果我的问题回答得分，那就上去吧。“
I mean, that's kind of a nice way to do things because you're kinda then taking them in, run around needing,
我的意思是，这是一种很好的做事方式，因为你有点接受它们，跑来跑去需要，
needing human beings, and yet you do have
需要人类，但你确实有
a clear numerical measure that's coming out the back end.
一个明确的数字测量，即后端出现。
But it sort of has some catches because, you know,
但它有一些捕获因为，你知道，
often there will be a fairly indirect connection between
通常会有一个相当间接的联系
your end task and the quality of the machine translation,
你的最终任务和机器翻译的质量，
and it might turn out that there certain aspects of
它可能会发现某些方面
the machine translation like whether you get agreement endings,
机器翻译就像你是否得到协议结束一样
right on nouns and verbs or something.
就名词和动词或其他东西而言。
They are actually just irrelevant to your performance in the task and say you're
它们实际上与你在任务中的表现无关，并说你是
not assessing all aspects of um, quality.
不评估um的所有方面，质量。
Um, and so then the third way to do it is to come up with
嗯，那么第三种方法就是想出来
some way to score the direct tasks.
某种方式来评分直接任务。
So, here, um, the direct task is machine translation,
所以，在这里，嗯，直接的任务是机器翻译，
and this has been a valuable tool.
这是一个很有价值的工具。
For, you know, really the last so
因为，你知道，真的是最后一次
25 years when people are doing machine learning models,
人们在做机器学习模型25年了
because as soon as you have an automatic way to score things,
因为只要你有自动的方式得分的东西，
you can then run automated experiments to say "Let me try out these 50 different options.
然后你可以运行自动化实验来说“让我尝试这50种不同的选择。
Let me start varying these hyper-parameters and work out which way to do things is best."
让我开始改变这些超参数，找出最好的做法。“
And that importance has only grown in the deep learning era,
这种重要性只有在深度学习时代才会增长，
when all the time what we want you to do is as Abby discussed, um,
什么时候我们想要你做的就像艾比讨论的那样，嗯，
build end-to-end systems and then back
建立端到端系统，然后再回来
propagate throughout the entire system to improve them,
在整个系统中传播以改善它们，
and we're doing that based on having
我们这样做是基于拥有
some objective measure which is our automatic metric.
一些客观测量，这是我们的自动度量。
And so, that led into the development of
因此，这导致了发展
automatic metrics to try and assess machine translation quality,
尝试评估机器翻译质量的自动指标，
and the most famous and still most used one is this one called BLEU.
而最着名且最常用的是这个名为BLEU的。
And so, as Abby briefly mentioned,
因此，正如Abby简要提到的，
we have a reference translation done by human beings.
我们有一个由人类完成的参考翻译。
At some time a human being has to translate each piece of source material once,
在某个时候，人类必须翻译每一个源材料一次，
but then you take a machine translation and you
但是你接受了机器翻译
score it based on the extent to which there
根据那里的程度得分
are one or more word sequences that appear in
是一个或多个出现的单词序列
the reference translation and also appear in the machine translation.
参考翻译也出现在机器翻译中。
And so you are working out n-gram preci-precision scores for different values of n. So,
因此，您正在计算不同n值的n-gram精确度分数。所以，
the standard way of doing it is you do it for one grams,
这样做的标准方法是你做一克，
bigrams, trigrams, and four-grams.
双胞胎，三卦和四克。
So, word sequences of size one to four,
所以，大小一到四的单词序列，
and you try and find for ones of those in the machine translation,
你尝试找到机器翻译中的那些，
whether they also appear in the reference translation,
他们是否也出现在参考译文中，
and there are two tricks at work here.
这里有两个技巧。
Um, one trick is you have to do a kind of a bipartite matching um,
嗯，一个诀窍就是你必须做一个双方匹配的嗯，
because it just can't be that um,
因为它不可能是那个，
there's a word um,
嗯，
in the, in the reference translation somewhere.
在，在某处的参考翻译中。
Um, [NOISE] I don't know if there's.
嗯，[NOISE]我不知道是否有。
I've got a good example here [NOISE].
我在这里有一个很好的例子[NOISE]。
Um, maybe I can only do a silly example,
嗯，也许我只能做一个愚蠢的例子，
but I'll do a silly example.
但我会做一个愚蠢的例子。
Um, that it's- it doesn't seem like you wanna say "Okay.
嗯，这似乎 - 你似乎不想说“好的。
Because there's a "the" in the reference,
因为参考中有“the”，
that means that this "the" is right and this "the" is right,
这意味着这个“the”是正确的，这个“the”是对的，
and this "the" is right and every other "the" is also right."
这个“这个”是正确的，而其他每个人“也是对的。”
That sort of seems unfair.
那种看起来不公平。
So, you're only allowed to use each thing in the reference once in matching n-grams,
所以，你只允许在匹配n-gram时使用引用中的每个东西，
but you are allowed to use it multiple times for different order n-grams.
但是你可以多次使用它来获得不同的订单n-gram。
So, you can use it both in the uh unigram,
所以，你可以在uh unigram中使用它，
bigram, trigram and 4-gram.
bigram，trigram和4克。
The other idea is that although you're measuring
另一个想法是，虽然你在测量
the precision of n-grams that are in the machine translation,
机器翻译中的n-gram精度，
you wouldn't want people to be able to cheat by
你不希望别人能够作弊
putting almost nothing into the machine translation.
几乎没有任何东西进入机器翻译。
So, you might wanna game it by no matter what the source document is.
因此，无论源文档是什么，您都可能想要游戏。
If the target language is English,
如果目标语言是英语，
you could just um say,
你可以这样说，
"My translation is the,
“我的翻译是，
because I'm pretty sure that will be in
因为我很确定会在
the reference translation somewhere and I'll get 0,3 unigram,
某处的参考译文，我会得到0,3 unigram，
and that's not great but I'll get something for that and I am done."
这不是很好，但我会得到一些东西，我完成了。“
And so you wouldn't want that and so,
所以你不会想要那样的，
you're then being penalized by something called the brevity penalty if
如果你被称为简短惩罚，那么你就会受到惩罚
your translation is shorter than the reference translation,
您的翻译比参考译文短，
and so this BLEU metric is um forming
所以这个BLEU指标正在形成
a geometric average of n-gram precision up to some n. Normally,
n-gram精度的几何平均值，最高可达n。一般，
it's sort of up to four,
它最多四个，
is how it's done.
它是如何完成的。
Where it's a weighted geometric average,
它是加权几何平均值，
where you're putting weights on the different n-grams.
你在不同的n-gram上加权。
Um, for the assignment, we're only using unigrams and bigrams.
嗯，对于任务，我们只使用unigrams和bigrams。
So, you could say that means we're putting a weight of zero on um,
所以，你可以说这意味着我们对你的重量为零，
the trigrams and 4-grams.
三卦和4克。
Okay. Um, and so that's basically what we're doing.
好的。嗯，这基本上就是我们正在做的事情。
I-I've just mentioned um couple of other things.
我刚刚提到了其他一些事情。
You might think that this is kind of random,
你可能认为这是随机的，
and so people have um,
人们有嗯，
used this idea of rather than just having one reference translation,
使用这个想法，而不是只有一个参考翻译，
we could have multiple reference translations,
我们可以有多个参考译文，
because that way we can allow for there being
因为这样我们可以允许存在
variation and good ways of translating things,
变化和翻译事物的好方法，
because in language there's always lots of good ways that you can translate one sentence.
因为在语言中总有很多好的方法可以翻译一个句子。
Um, people have done that quite a bit,
嗯，人们已经做了很多，
but people have also decided that even if you have one translation,
但人们也决定，即使你有一个翻译，
provided it's independent and on a kind of statistical basis,
如果它是独立的并且基于某种统计基础，
you're still more likely to match it if your translation is a good translation.
如果你的翻译是一个很好的翻译，你仍然更有可能匹配它。
So, it's probably okay.
所以，它可能还可以。
Um, so when BLEU was originally um, introduced,
嗯，所以当BLEU原来是嗯，介绍，
BLEU seemed marvelous and people drew graphs like this showing how
BLEU似乎很了不起，人们画了这样的图表，显示了如何
closely BLEU scores correlated um,
密切BLEU分数相关，嗯，
with human judgments of translation quality.
与人类判断翻译质量。
However, um, like a lot of things in life,
但是，嗯，就像生活中的很多事情一样，
there are a lot of things that are great measures,
有很多很重要的事情，
providing people aren't directly trying to optimize it,
提供人不是直接尝试优化它，
and so what's happened since then um,
从那以后发生了什么事，嗯，
is that everybody has been trying to optimize BLEU scores,
是每个人都在努力优化BLEU分数，
and the result of that is that BLEU scores have gone up massively but the correlation
结果就是BLEU分数大幅上升但相关性上升
between BLEU scores and human judgments of
BLEU分数与人类判断之间的关系
translation in quality have gone down massively,
质量翻译量大幅下降，
and so we're in this current state that um, the BLEU scores,
所以我们现在处于这样的状态，即BLEU得分，
the machines, um are pretty near the scores of human translations.
机器，嗯非常接近人类翻译的分数。
So, you know, according to BLEU scores,
所以，你知道，根据BLEU分数，
we're producing almost human quality machine translation,
我们正在生产几乎人性化的机器翻译，
but if you actually look at the real quality of the translations,
但如果你真的看看翻译的真实质量，
they're still well behind
他们仍然落后
human beings um and because you could say the metric is being gamed.
人类嗯，因为你可以说这个指标正在被游戏。
Okay. I'll hope those things help for giving more sense um for assignment four.
好的。我希望这些东西有助于赋予作业四更多的意义。
Um, so now for the last um,
嗯，现在是最后一个，
about 12 minutes, um,
大约12分钟，嗯，
I just now wanna um,
我刚才想要，
return to um final projects and say a little bit more um about final projects.
回到最后的项目并对最终项目说多一点。
Um so, there many,
恩，有很多，
many different ways you can do final projects,
你可以通过多种方式完成最终项目，
but just to sort of go through the steps.
但只是为了完成这些步骤。
I mean, you know, for a simple straightforward project,
我的意思是，你知道，对于一个简单直接的项目，
this is kind of the steps that you want to go through.
这是您想要经历的一些步骤。
So, you choose some tasks,
所以，你选择了一些任务，
summarizing text um, producing a shorter version of a text.
总结文本，生成较短版本的文本。
You work out some dataset that you can use.
您可以找出一些可以使用的数据集。
So, this is an example of the kind of tasks that there
所以，这是那种任务的一个例子
are academic data sets for that other people have used,
是其他人使用的学术数据集，
and so you could just use one of those,
所以你可以使用其中一个，
and that's it, you're already done or you could think "Oh no!
就是这样，你已经完成了，或者你可以想到“哦不！
I'm much too creative for that.
我太有创意了。
I'm gonna come up with my own dataset [NOISE] um and get some online source and do it."
我会想出我自己的数据集[NOISE]嗯，并获得一些在线资源并做到这一点。“
Um, and you know,
嗯，你知道，
summaries of the kind of things you can find online and produce your own dataset.
您可以在线找到并生成自己的数据集的摘要。
Um [NOISE] I wanna say a bit in,
嗯[NOISE]我想说一点，
in just after this,
在此之后，
about separating off um data sets for
关于分离um数据集
training and test data, so I'll delay that, but that's important.
培训和测试数据，所以我会推迟，但这很重要。
Then, you want to work out a way to evaluate your um,
然后，你想找到一种方法来评估你的嗯，
system including an automatic evaluation.
系统包括自动评估。
Um, normally, for summarization,
嗯，通常，用于摘要，
people use a slightly different metric called
人们使用一种稍微不同的度量标准
ROUGE but it's sort of related to BLEU hence its name.
ROUGE但它有点与BLEU有关，因此它的名字。
Um, it's the same story that it sort of works,
嗯，这是同样的故事，它有点工作，
but human evaluation is much better.
但人的评价要好得多。
Um, but you need- so you need to work out some metrics you can use for the project.
嗯，但是你需要 - 所以你需要制定一些可以用于项目的指标。
Um, the next thing you should do is establish a baseline.
嗯，你应该做的下一件事是建立一个基线。
So, if it's a well-worked on problem there might already be one,
所以，如果它是一个很好的问题，可能已经有一个，
but it's not bad to try and calculate one for yourself anyway,
但无论如何，尝试为自己计算一个也不错，
and in particular what you should first have is
特别是你应该首先拥有的是什么
a very simple model and see how well it works.
一个非常简单的模型，看看它的工作情况。
So, for human language material,
所以，对于人类语言材料，
often doing things like bag of words models,
经常做像字袋模型，
whether they're just a simple classifier over
他们是否只是一个简单的分类器
words or a new bag of words, averaging word vectors.
单词或一包新单词，平均单词向量。
It's just useful to try that on the task and see how it works,
尝试完成任务并了解它是如何工作的，这很有用，
see what kinds of things it already gets right,
看看它已经得到了什么样的东西，
what kind of things it gets wrong.
它出了什么样的错误。
You know, one possibility is you will find that
你知道，有一种可能性就是你会发现的
a very simple model already does great on your task.
一个非常简单的模型已经完成了你的任务。
If that's the case, um,
如果是这样的话，嗯，
you have too easy a task,
你太容易了，
and you probably need to find a task that's more challenging to work on. Um, yes.
你可能需要找到一个更具挑战性的任务。嗯，是的。
So after that, you'll then sort of think about what could be a good kind
那么在那之后，你会想到什么是好的
of neural network model that might do well, implement it,
神经网络模型可能做得很好，实现它，
test it um, see what kind of errors that makes and you know,
测试它，看看有什么样的错误，你知道，
that's sort of if you've gotten that far,
如果你已经走得那么远，
you're sort of in the right space for a class project.
你是一个适合课堂项目的合适空间。
But, you know, it's sort of hoped that you could do more than that.
但是，你知道，有点希望你能做更多的事情。
But after you've seen the errors from the first version,
但是在你看到第一个版本的错误后，
you could think about how to make it better and come up with a better project,
你可以考虑如何让它更好，并提出一个更好的项目，
and so I would encourage everyone,
所以我鼓励大家，
you know, you really do want to look at the data, right?
你知道吗，你确实想查看数据，对吧？
You don't just wanna be sort of having things and files and run and say "Okay, 0,71.
你不只是想拥有一些东西和文件，然后跑去说“好吧，0,71。
Let me make some random change 0,70.
让我随机改变0,70。
Oh, that's not a good one," repeat over.
哦，那不是一个好的，“重复一遍。
You actually want to be sort of looking at your dataset in any way you can.
实际上，您希望以任何方式查看数据集。
It's good to visualize the dataset to understand what's
可视化数据集以了解数据集是很好的
important in it that you might be able to take advantage of,
你可以利用它的重要性，
you want to be able to look at what kind of
你希望能够看到什么样的
errors are being made because that might give you
因为这可能会给你带来错误
ideas of how you could put more stuff into the model that would do better.
关于如何将更多东西放入模型中以便做得更好的想法。
Um, you might wanna do some graphing of the effect of hyper-parameters,
嗯，你可能想做一些超参数影响的图表，
so you can kind of understand that better.
所以你可以更好地理解。
And so, the hope is that you will try out
所以，希望你会尝试
some other kinds of models and make things better.
其他一些模型，让事情变得更好。
And sort of one of the goals here is,
而这里的目标之一是，
it's good if you've sort of got a well-setup experimental setup,
如果您有一个设置良好的实验设置，这是很好的，
so you can easily turn around experiments because then you're just more
所以你可以很容易地扭转实验，因为那样你就更多了
likely to be able to try several things in the time available.
可能在可用的时间内尝试几件事。
Okay. Um, couple of other things I wanted to mention.
好的。嗯，我想提到的其他几件事。
Um, one is sort of different amounts of data.
嗯，一个是不同数量的数据。
So, it's really, really important for all the stuff that we do,
所以，对我们所做的所有事情来说，这真的非常重要，
that we have different sets of data.
我们有不同的数据集。
So, we have trained data,
所以，我们有训练的数据，
we have dev test data,
我们有开发测试数据，
we have test data at least,
我们至少有测试数据，
and sometimes it's useful to have even,
有时甚至是有用的，
um, more data available.
嗯，有更多可用数据。
So, for many of the public datasets, they're already split into different subsets like this,
因此，对于许多公共数据集，它们已经分成不同的子集，如下所示，
but there are some that aren't.
但也有一些不是。
There are some that might only have a training set,
有一些可能只有训练集，
and a test set.
和测试集。
And what you don't want to do is think,
而你不想做的就是思考，
"Oh, there's only a training set and a test set.
“哦，只有训练集和测试集。
Therefore I'll just run every time on the test set."
因此，我每次都会在测试集上运行。“
That- that's a really invalid way to go about your research.
那 - 这对你的研究来说是一种无效的方式。
So, if there aren't
所以，如果没有
dev sets available or you need to do some more tuning,
dev设置可用或者您需要进行更多调整，
and you need some separate tuning data,
你需要一些单独的调整数据，
you sort of have to, um,
你有点必须，嗯，
make it for yourself by splitting off some of the training data,
通过分割一些训练数据为自己做，
and not using it for the basic training and using it for tuning,
而不是用它来进行基础训练并用它进行调整，
and fo- as dev data.
和开发数据。
Um, yes.
嗯，是的。
So, to go on about that, um, more, more.
所以，继续关于那个，嗯，更多，更多。
So, the basic issue is this issue of fitting and overfitting to particular datasets.
因此，基本问题是适应和过度拟合特定数据集的问题。
So, when we train a model, um,
那么，当我们训练一个模型时，嗯，
on some training data,
关于一些培训数据，
we train it and the error rate goes down.
我们训练它，错误率下降。
And over time, we gradually overfit to the training data because we sort of
随着时间的推移，我们逐渐适应训练数据，因为我们有点
pick up on our neural network f- facts about the particular training data items,
了解有关特定训练数据项的神经网络f-事实，
and we just sort of start to learn them.
我们只是开始学习它们。
Now in the old days,
现在在过去，
the fact that you overfit to the training data was seen as evil.
你过度训练训练数据的事实被认为是邪恶的。
In modern neural network think,
在现代神经网络中思考，
we don't think it is evil what we overfit to the training data
我们不认为我们过度训练数据是邪恶的
because all neural nets that are any good overfit to the training data,
因为所有的神经网都对训练数据有任何好处，
and we would be very sad if they didn't.
如果他们不这样做，我们会非常难过。
I'll come back to that in a moment.
我马上回过头来看看。
But nevertheless, they're overfitting like crazy.
但尽管如此，它们仍然过于疯狂。
So, what we, but and what we want to build is something that generalizes well.
那么，我们，但是我们想要构建的东西是能够很好地概括的东西。
So, we have to have some separate data,
所以，我们必须有一些单独的数据，
that's our validation data,
这是我们的验证数据，
and say look at what performance looks like on the validation data.
并说看看验证数据的性能。
And commonly we find that training up until some point,
通常我们发现训练直到某一点，
improves our performance on separate validation data,
提高我们在单独验证数据上的表现，
and then we start to overfit to
然后我们开始适应
the training data in a way that our validation set performance gets worse.
训练数据的方式使我们的验证集性能变差。
Um, and so, then,
那么，那么，
further training on the training data isn't useful because we're starting
由于我们正在开始，因此对培训数据进行进一步培训是没有用的
to build a model that generalizes worse when run on other data.
构建一个在其他数据上运行时概括得更糟的模型。
But there's- the whole point here is,
但是 - 这里的重点是，
we can only do this experiment if our validation data is separate from our training data.
如果我们的验证数据与我们的培训数据分开，我们只能进行此实验。
If it's the same data or if it's overlapping data,
如果它是相同的数据或者它是重叠的数据，
we can't draw this graph.
我们无法绘制此图表。
Um, and so, therefore, we can't do valid experiments.
嗯，因此，我们不能做有效的实验。
Um, now you might think, "Oh, well,
嗯，现在你可能会想，“哦，好吧，
maybe I can, um,
也许我可以，嗯，
do this and just use the test set of data."
这样做只需使用测试数据集。“
Um, but that's also invalid,
嗯，但那也无效，
and the reason why that's invalid is,
以及那个无效的原因是，
as you do experiments,
当你做实验时，
you also start slowly over fitting to your development data.
你也开始慢慢适应你的开发数据。
So, the standard practice is you do a run and you get a score on the development data.
因此，标准做法是您进行运行并获得开发数据的分数。
You do a second run.
你再做一次。
You do worse on the development data,
你在开发数据上做得更糟，
and so you throw that second model away.
所以你扔掉了第二个模型。
You do a third experiment.
你做了第三个实验。
You do better on the development data,
你在开发数据方面做得更好，
and so you keep that model and you repeat over 50 times.
所以你保持这个模型，你重复超过50次。
And while some of those subsequent models you keep,
而你保留的一些后续模型，
are genuinely better because you sort of worked out something good to do.
真的更好，因为你有点做了好事。
But it turns out that some of those subsequent models only sort of just happened.
但事实证明，其中一些后续模型只是恰好发生了。
You just got lucky and they happened to score better on the development data.
你很幸运，他们碰巧在开发数据上得分更高。
And so, if you kind of keep repeating that process 60 or 100 times,
所以，如果你继续重复这个过程60或100次，
you're also gradually [NOISE] overfitting on your development data,
你也逐渐[NOISE]过度拟合你的开发数据，
and you get unrealistically good dev scores.
并且你得到了不切实际的好的开发分数。
And so, that means two things.
所以，这意味着两件事。
You know, if you want to be rigorous and do a huge amount of hyper-parameter exploration,
你知道，如果你想要严谨并进行大量的超参数探索，
it can be good to have a second development se- test set,
拥有第二个开发测试集可能会很好，
so that you have one, that you haven't overfit as much.
所以你有一个，你没有那么多。
And if you want to have valid scores on te-
如果你想获得有效的分数
on as to what is my actual performance on independent data,
关于我在独立数据上的实际表现，
it's vital that you have separate test data that you are
您拥有独立的测试数据至关重要
not using at all in this process, right?
在这个过程中完全不使用，对吧？
So, the ideal state is that,
所以，理想的状态是，
for your real test data, um,
对于你真实的测试数据，嗯，
that you never used it at all until you've finished training your data, uh,
在你完成数据训练之前，你根本就没用过它，呃，
training your model, and then you run your final model once on the test data,
训练你的模型，然后在测试数据上运行你的最终模型，
and you write up your paper and those are your results.
你写了你的论文，这些都是你的结果。
Now, I will be honest and say the world usually isn't
现在，我会诚实地说世界通常不是
quite that perfect because after you've done that,
非常完美，因为在你完成之后，
you then go to sleep [NOISE] and wake up thinking.
然后你去睡觉[NOISE]并醒来思考。
"I've got a fantastic idea of how to make my model better."
“我对如何让我的模型变得更好有一个很棒的想法。”
and you run off and implement that,
你跑掉并实施，
and it works great on the dev data,
它在开发数据上运行得很好，
and then for you, run it on the test data again and the numbers go up.
然后为你，再次在测试数据上运行它，数字上升。
Um, sort of everybody does that.
嗯，每个人都这样做。
Um, and you know,
嗯，你知道，
in modicum it's okay,
在modicum它没关系，
you know, if that means you occasionally run on the test data it's not so bad, um,
你知道吗，如果那意味着你偶尔会运行测试数据就不会那么糟糕，嗯，
but you really need to be aware of the slippery slope because,
但是你真的需要注意滑坡，因为，
if you then start falling into, "I've got a new model.
如果你开始陷入困境，“我有一个新的模型。
Let me try that one on the test data.
让我尝试一下测试数据。
I've got a new model. Let me try this one on the test data."
我有一个新的模型。让我试试这个测试数据吧。“
Then you're just sort of overfitting to the test data,
然后你只是过度拟合测试数据，
and getting an unrealistically high score.
并得到一个不切实际的高分。
And that's precisely why a lot of the competitions like Kaggle competitions,
而这正是很多比赛如Kaggle比赛的原因，
have a secret test dataset that you can't run on.
有一个你无法运行的秘密测试数据集。
So, that they can do a genuine,
所以，他们可以做一个真实的，
independent test on the actual test data.
对实际测试数据进行独立测试。
Okay. Um, let's see, um, a couple more minutes.
好的。嗯，让我们看看，嗯，还有几分钟。
So, yeah, getting your neural network to train.
所以，是的，让你的神经网络训练。
Um, my two messages are, you know,
嗯，我的两条消息是，你知道，
first of all, you should start with a positive attitude.
首先，你应该以积极的态度开始。
Neural networks want to learn.
神经网络想要学习。
If they're not learning,
如果他们不学习，
you're doing something to stop them from learning.
你正在做些什么来阻止他们学习。
And so, you should just stop that,
所以，你应该停下来，
and they will learn because they want to learn.
他们会因为想要学习而学习。
They're just like little children.
他们就像小孩子一样。
Um, but, if the follow up to that is the grim reality that there are just tons
嗯，但是，如果跟进这个是严峻的现实，只有吨
of things you can do that will cause
你可以做的事情会导致
your neural networks not to learn very well or at all,
你的神经网络不能很好地学习，或者根本不会
and this is the frustrating part of
这是令人沮丧的一部分
this whole field because you know, it's not like a compile error.
整个领域因为你知道，它不像编译错误。
It can just be hard to find and fix them.
它很难找到并修复它们。
And, you know, it is just really
而且，你知道，这只是真的
standard that you spend more time dealing with trying to find,
标准，你花更多的时间来寻找，
and fix why it doesn't work well and getting it to work well than
并解决为什么它不能正常工作并使其运行良好
you- than the time you spent writing the code for your model.
你 - 比你为模型编写代码的时间。
So, remember to budget for that when you're doing your final project,
所以，记得在你做最后的项目时为此预算，
it just won't work if you finish the code a day or two before the deadline.
如果你在截止日期前一两天完成代码就行不通。
Um, so, you need to work out what those things are,
嗯，所以，你需要弄清楚那些东西是什么，
"That can be hard," but you know experience,
“那可能很难，”但你知道经验，
experimental care, rules of thumb help.
实验护理，经验法则帮助。
So, there are just lots of things that are important.
所以，有很多重要的事情。
So, you know, your learning rates are important.
所以，你知道，你的学习率很重要。
If your learning rates are way too high, things won't learn.
如果你的学习率过高，事情就无法学习。
If your learning rates are way too low,
如果你的学习率太低，
they will learn very slowly and badly.
他们会慢慢地学习。
Um, initialization makes a difference.
嗯，初始化有所作为。
Having good initialization often determines how well neural networks, um, learn.
良好的初始化通常决定了神经网络的学习能力。
Um, I have a separate slide here that I probably haven't got time to go
嗯，我在这里有一张单独的幻灯片，我可能还没有时间去
through all of on sort of for sequence [NOISE] models,
通过所有的序列[NOISE]模型，
some of the tips of what people normally think are
人们通常认为的一些提示
good ways to get those models, um, working.
获得这些模型的好方法，嗯，工作。
But I'll just say this one last thing.
但我最后会说这个。
Um, I think the strategy that you really want to
嗯，我认为你真正想要的策略
take is to work incrementally and build up slowly.
采取是逐步工作，慢慢积累。
It just doesn't work to think,
它只是无法思考，
"Oh I've got the mother of all models,
“哦，我有所有型号的母亲，
and build this enormously complex thing,
并构建这个非常复杂的东西，
and then run it on the data,
然后在数据上运行它，
and it crashes and burns."
它崩溃和烧伤。“
You have no idea what to do at that point,
你不知道该做什么，
that the only good way is to sort of build up slowly.
唯一好办法就是慢慢积累。
So [NOISE] start with a very simple model,
所以[NOISE]从一个非常简单的模型开始，
get it to work,
让它工作，
add your bells and whistles,
加上你的花里胡哨，
extra layers and so on.
额外的图层等。
Get them to work or abandon them.
让他们工作或放弃他们。
And so, try and proceed from one working model to another as much as possible.
因此，尽可能尝试从一种工作模式进入另一种工作模式。
One of- another way that you can start small and build up is with data.
另一种可以从小开始构建的方法是使用数据。
The easiest way to see bugs and problems in your model,
查看模型中的错误和问题的最简单方法，
is with the minutest possible amount of data.
是尽可能少的数据。
So, start with a dataset of eight items.
因此，从八个项目的数据集开始。
Sometimes it's even best if those eight items are ones that are
有时，如果那八个项目是那些，那就更好了
artificial data that you designed yourself
你自己设计的人工数据
because then you can often more easily see problems,
因为那时你经常可以更容易地看到问题，
and what's going wrong.
出了什么问题。
So, you should train on that,
所以，你应该训练，
um, because it's only eight items,
嗯，因为它只有八个项目，
training will only take seconds,
训练只需几秒钟，
and that's really, really useful for being able to iterate quickly.
这对于能够快速迭代非常有用。
And you know, if you can't have your model get
而且你知道，如果你不能得到你的模型
100 percent accuracy on training and testing on those eight examples,
对这八个例子进行培训和测试的准确率为100％，
well, you know, either the model is woefully under powered or the model is broken,
好吧，你知道，要么模型很糟糕，要么模型坏了，
and you've got clear things to do right there.
而你在那里有明确的事情要做。
Um, when you go to a bigger model, um,
嗯，当你去一个更大的模特，嗯，
the standard practice with modern neural networks is,
现代神经网络的标准实践是，
you want to train your models.
你想训练你的模特。
You want models that can overfit massively on the training set.
你想要的模型可以在训练集上大量适应。
So, in general, your models should still be getting
所以，一般来说，你的模型应该仍然存在
close to 100 percent accuracy on the training set after you've
在你训练之后接近100％的准确率
trained it for a long time because powerful neural network models are
因为强大的神经网络模型，它已经训练了很长时间
just really good at over-fitting to, and memorizing data.
真的很擅长过度拟合和记忆数据。
Um, if that's not the case well, you know,
嗯，如果情况不是这样，你知道，
maybe you want a bigger model.
也许你想要一个更大的模型。
Maybe you want to have higher hidden dimensions or
也许你想拥有更高的隐藏尺寸或
add an extra layer to your neural network or something like that.
在你的神经网络中添加一个额外的层或类似的东西。
You shouldn't be scared of overfitting on the training data.
你不应该害怕过度拟合训练数据。
But once you've proved you can do that,
但是，一旦你证明你可以做到这一点，
you then do want a model that also generalizes well.
然后你想要一个也能很好地推广的模型。
And so, normally the way that you're addressing that is then by regularizing the model,
因此，通常通过规范模型来解决问题的方式，
and there are different ways to regularize your model,
并且有不同的方法来规范您的模型，
but we talked about in the assignment, doing dropout.
但我们在任务中谈到了辍学问题。
I mean, using generous dropout is
我的意思是，使用慷慨的辍学是
one very common and effective strategy for regularizing your models.
一种非常常见且有效的策略，用于规范您的模型。
And so, then you've, what you want to be doing is regularizing
所以，那么你，你想要做的就是正规化
your model enough that the curve no longer looks like this,
你的模型足够曲线不再像这样，
but instead that your validation performance kind of levels out,
但相反，你的验证性能水平，
but doesn't start ramping back up again,
但是没有开始再次升级，
and that's then a sort of a sign of a well regularized model.
那是一种正规化模型的标志。
Okay. I will stop there,
好的。我会在那里停下来
and then we'll come back to the question-answering project on Thursday.
然后我们将在周四回到问答项目。